<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:00:15 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Messier 66 Close Up</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 09:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Big, beautifullies a mere 35 million light-years away.Theis about 100 thousand light-years across, similar in size to the Milky Way.Thisclose-up view spans a region about 30,000light-years wide around the galactic core.It shows the galaxy&amp;rsquo;s disk dramatically inclined to our line-of-sight.Surrounding its bright core, the likely home of a supermassive blackhole, obscuring dust lanes and young, blue star clusters sweepdotted with the tell-tale glow of pinkish star forming regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sh2-132 The Lion Nebula</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/natalia_lewandowska/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 09:00:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/natalia_lewandowska/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Imran Badr
Is the Lion Nebula the real ruler of the ? This powerful feline appearing is powered by two , each with a mass over 20 times greater than . Formed from that have expanded, the nebula&amp;rsquo;s energetic matter not only , but is dense enough to contract . The angular size of the Nebula, officially named 2-132, is slightly greater than that of the . The gaseous resides about 10,000 s away in a named after the King of in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadow of a Martian Robot</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 09:00:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
What if you saw your shadow on Mars and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t human? Then you might be the exploring . Perseverance has been examining the Red Planet since 2021, of its complex and , and sending across the inner . in February of 2024, opposite the Sun and across Neretva Vallis in , with a at the top of the frame. The distinctively non-human shadow of the is visible below center, superposed on .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stereo Helene</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/iss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 09:00:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/iss/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Cassini Imaging Team
Get out yourred/blue glasses and float next to Helene,small, icy moon of Saturn.is a Trojan moon, so called because it orbits at a.A Lagrange point is a gravitationally stable positionnear two massive bodies, in this case.In fact, irregularly shaped ( about 36 by 32 by 30 kilometers)Helene orbits at Dione&amp;rsquo;s leading Lagrange point whilebrotherly ice moon Polydeuces follows at Dione&amp;rsquo;s trailing Lagrangepoint. was constructed from twoCassini images captured during in 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Solar Filament Erupts</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gsfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 09:00:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gsfc/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
What&amp;rsquo;s happened to our Sun? Nothing very unusual &amp;ndash; it just .Toward the middle of 2012, a standing suddenly erupted into space, producing an energetic (CME). had been held up for days by the Sun&amp;rsquo;s ever changing and the timing of the eruption was . by the Sun-orbiting Solar Dynamics Observatory, the resulting electrons and ions into the Solar System, some of which arrived at Earth three days later and impacted Earth&amp;rsquo;s , causing visible .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manicouagan Impact Crater from Space</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/expedition_59/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 09:01:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/expedition_59/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Orbiting 400 kilometers above Quebec, Canada, planet Earth, theInternational Space Stationthis snapshot of the broadSt. Lawrence River and curiously circular Lake Manicouagan on April 11.Right of center, the ring-shaped lake is awithin the eroded remnant of an ancient 100 kilometerdiameter impact crater.The ancient crater is very,a visible reminder that Earth is vulnerable to.Over 200 million years old, the Manicouagan crater waslikely caused by the impact of a rocky body about5 kilometers in diameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M78 from the Euclid Space Telescope</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/euclid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 09:00:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/euclid/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: ESA
Star formation can be messy.To help find out just how messy, &amp;rsquo;s new recently captured the most detailed image ever of the bright star forming region M78.Near the image center, lies at a distance of only about 1,300 s away and has a main glowing core that spans about 5 light-years. The was taken in both and light.The purple tint in is caused by dark preferentially ing the blue light of hot, young stars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling NGC 3169</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aziz_kaeouach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 09:01:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aziz_kaeouach/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Christophe Vergnes
Spiral galaxy NGC 3169 looks to be unraveling like a ball of cosmicyarn.It lies some 70 million light-years away,bright star Regulus toward the faint constellation Sextans.Wound up spiral arms are pulled out into sweeping tidaltails as NGC 3169 (left) and neighboring NGC 3166.Eventually the galaxies will merge into one,a common fate even for bright galaxies in.Drawn out stellar arcs and plumes are clearindications of the ongoing gravitational interactionsacross the deep and colorful photo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CG4 The Globule and the Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/t._a._rector/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 09:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/t._a._rector/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: CTIO
Can a gas cloud eat a galaxy? It&amp;rsquo;s not even close. The &amp;ldquo;claw&amp;rdquo; of this odd looking &amp;ldquo;creature&amp;rdquo; in the is a gas cloud known as a . This globule, however, . Cometary are typically characterized by heads andelongated . These features cause cometary to have visual similarities to s, but in reality they are very much different. are frequently the birthplaces of stars, and many show very young in their heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aurora Dome Sky</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yuxuan_liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 09:00:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yuxuan_liu/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Xuecheng Liu
It seemed like night, but part of the sky glowed purple. It was the now famous night of May 10, 2024, when .The featured image was captured this night during early morning hours from , , .The panorama is a composite of several 6-second exposures covering two thirds of the visible sky, with in the center, and processed to heighten the colors and remove electrical wires.The photographer (in the foreground) reported that the appeared to flow from a point overhead but illuminated the sky only toward the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AR 3664 Giant Sunspot Group</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gruppo_astrofili_palidoro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 09:00:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gruppo_astrofili_palidoro/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Guiseppe Conzo
Right now, one of the largest sunspot groups in recent history is crossing the Sun. is not only big &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s violent, throwing off clouds of particles into the .Some of these s are already impacting the Earth, and others might follow. At the extreme, could cause some , the to slightly distort, and .When impacting , these particles can produce beautiful auroras, with some already being reported .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Hole Accreting with Jet</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 09:00:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/swift/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
What happens when a black hole devours a star? Many details remain unknown, but observations are providing new clues.In 2014, a was recorded by the ground-based robotic telescopes of the (Project ASAS-SN), with followed-up observations by instruments including &amp;rsquo;s Earth-orbiting .Computer modeling of these emissions fit a star being by a distant . The results of such a collision are portrayed in the .The itself is a depicted as a tiny black dot in the center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 ATs</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnegie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 09:00:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnegie/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Yuri Beletsky
Despite their resemblance to,these three are not the droids you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.Instead, the enclosures house 1.8 meter(ATs) at Paranal Observatory in theregion of Chile.The ATs are designed to be used,a technique for achieving extremely high resolution observations,in concert with the observatory&amp;rsquo;s 8 meter.A total of four ATs are operational, eachfitted with a transporterthe telescope along a track allowing different arrays with the large unittelescopes.To work as an interferometer, the light from each telescopeis brought to a common focal point by a systemof mirrors in underground tunnels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IC 1795 The Fishhead Nebula</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mauro_narduzzi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 09:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mauro_narduzzi/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Roberto Colombari
To some, this nebula looks like the head of a .However, really features clouds in IC 1795,a star forming region in the northern .The nebula&amp;rsquo;s colors were created by adopting thefor mapping narrowband emissions from oxygen, hydrogen,and sulfur atoms to blue, green and red colors, and furtherblending the data with images of the region recorded throughbroadband filters.Not far on the sky from the famous in Perseus, IC 1795 is itself located next to IC 1805,the , as part of a that lieat the edge of a large molecular cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comet, Planet, Moon</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/starry_earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 09:00:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/starry_earth/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Juan Carlos Casado
Three bright objects satisfied seasoned stargazers of the western sky just after sunset earlier this month.The most familiar was , seen on the upper left in a crescent .The rest of the Moon was by sunlight first reflected by .The bright planet , the largest planet in , is seen to the upper left. Most unusual was , below the Moon and showing a stubby dust tail on the right but an ion .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rings Around the Ring Nebula</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/large_binocular_telescope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 09:01:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/large_binocular_telescope/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Hubble
The is more complicated than it appears through a small telescope. The easily visible is about one across,but - a combining data from three different large telescopes -the looping filaments of glowing gas extending much farther from &amp;rsquo;s central star.This includes red light emitted by hydrogen as well asvisible and .The Ring Nebula is an elongated , a type of nebula created when a -like star evolves to and become a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Sky Moon Shadow</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 09:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Tunc Tezel
but the sky is dark and the horizon is bright all around,you might be standing in the Moon&amp;rsquo;s shadow during a total eclipse ofthe Sun.In fact, the all-sky Moon shadow shown in thiscomposited panoramic view was capturedfrom a farm near Shirley, Arkansas, planet Earth.The exposures were made under clear skies during the.For that location near the center line of the Moon&amp;rsquo;s shadow track,totality lasted over 4 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Eclipse and Comets</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tsinghua_u./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 09:00:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tsinghua_u./</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Lin Zixuan
Not one, but two comets appeared near the Sun during .The expected comet was , but it was disappointingly dimmer than many had hoped.However, relatively unknown in long duration camera exposures. was the 5008th comet identified on images taken by &amp;amp; &amp;rsquo;s Sun-orbiting . Likely much smaller, Comet SOHO-5008 was a sungrazer which as it passed too . The featured image is not only unusual for capturing during an eclipse, but one of the that a has been photographed from the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filaments of the Vela Supernova Remnant</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/noirlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 09:01:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/noirlab/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: CTIO
The explosion is over, but the consequences continue. About eleven thousand years ago, a star in the constellation of could be seen to , creating a strange point of light briefly visible to humans living near the beginning of . The outer layers of the star crashed into the , driving a that is still visible today. The captures some of that filamentary and gigantic shock in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planets Around a Total Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 09:00:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Stéphane Vetter
What wonders appear when the Moon blocks the Sun?For many eager observers of of the Sun, the suddenly dark sky included the expected corona and two (perhaps surprise) planets: .Normally, in recent days, Venus is visible only in the morning when the Sun and Jupiter are below the horizon, while Jupiter appears bright only in the evening. On Monday, though, for well-placed observers, both planets became easily visible during the day right in line with the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwinding M51</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 09:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Hubble Heritage Project
The arms of a grand design spiral galaxy 60,000 light-years across areunwound in this digital transformation of the magnificent 2005.In fact, M51 is one of the original spiral nebulae, its windingarms described by a mathematical curve known as a, a spiral whose separation grows in away with increasing distance from the center.Applying logarithms to shift the pixelcoordinates in the Hubble image relative to the center of M51 mapsthe galaxy&amp;rsquo;s spiral arms into diagonal straight lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Solar Eclipse Below the Bottom of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
In late 2021 there was a total solar eclipse visible only at the end of the Earth. To capture the , airplanes took flight below the clouded seascape of .The shows one relatively spectacular capture where the bright spot is the outer of the Sun and the is seen as the dark spot in the center. A wing and engine of the are visible across the left and bottom of the image, while is visible on the far left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back at an Eclipsed Earth</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Mir 27 Crew
Here is what the Earth looks like during a.Theof the can be seen darkening part of.This moved the at nearly 2000 kilometers per hour.Only near the center of the see a total solar eclipse -others see a partial eclipse where only part of the.This of the 1999 August 11was one of the last evertaken from the .The two bright spots that appear on the upper left are thought to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ares 3 Landing Site The Martian Revisited</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 09:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: HiRISE
the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter&amp;rsquo;sHiRISE camera shows weathered craters and windblown deposits in southern.A striking shade of blue in standard HiRISE image colors,to the human eye the area would probably look grey or a little reddish.But human eyes have not gazedacross this terrain, unless you count the eyes of NASA astronautsin the scifi novel by Andy Weir.The novel chronicles the adventures of Mark Watney,an astronaut stranded at the fictional Mars mission Ares 3 landing sitecorresponding to the coordinates of this cropped HiRISE frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Full Plankton Moon</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
What glows in the night?This night a combination of usual and unusual glows.Perhaps the most usual glow was from, a potentially familiar object.The full Moon&amp;rsquo;s nearly results from the observer being near.As the Moon sets, ands in preferentially scatter out blue light, makingthe appear reddish whennear the horizon. Perhaps the mostwas from the bioluminescent, likely less familiar objects.These glow blue, it is thought, primarily toand.In this case, the glow was caused primarily byplankton-containing waves crashing onto the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Total Eclipse at the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:00:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Fred Bruenjes
Would you go to the end of the world to see a total eclipse of the Sun?If you did, would you be surprised to find someone else In 2003, the , the Moon, Antarctica, and two photographers all lined up in during an unusual. Even given the extreme location, a group of ventured near thebottom of the world to momentarydisappearance of the . One of the treasures collected was the &amp;ndash; a composite of four separate imagesdigitally combined to realistically simulate how the adaptive human the eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tarantula Zone</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:00:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Robert Gendler
,also known as 30 Doradus, is more than a thousand light-years in diameter,a giant star forming region within nearby satellite galaxy the.About 180 thousand light-years away, it&amp;rsquo;s the largest,most violent star forming region known in the whole LocalGroup of galaxies.The cosmic arachnid sprawls across,an assembly of image data from large space- and ground-based telescopes. (NGC 2070),intense radiation, stellar winds, and supernova shocksfrom the central young cluster of massive stars cataloged as R136energize the nebular glow and shape the spidery filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
