<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 09:00:49 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Cigar Galaxy from Hubble and Webb</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 09:00:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Something strange happened to this galaxy, but what?Known as the and cataloged as , red glowing gas and dust are being cast out from the center. Although this was surely stirred up by a recent pass near its , large spiral galaxy , this doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully explain the source of the red-glowing outwardly expanding gas and . Evidence indicates that this material is being driven out by the combined emerging of many stars, together creating a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planets Around a Total Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 09:00:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Stéphane Vetter
What wonders appear when the Moon blocks the Sun?For many eager observers of of the Sun, the suddenly dark sky included the expected corona and two (perhaps surprise) planets: .Normally, in recent days, Venus is visible only in the morning when the Sun and Jupiter are below the horizon, while Jupiter appears bright only in the evening. On Monday, though, for well-placed observers, both planets became easily visible during the day right in line with the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwinding M51</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 09:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Hubble Heritage Project
The arms of a grand design spiral galaxy 60,000 light-years across areunwound in this digital transformation of the magnificent 2005.In fact, M51 is one of the original spiral nebulae, its windingarms described by a mathematical curve known as a, a spiral whose separation grows in away with increasing distance from the center.Applying logarithms to shift the pixelcoordinates in the Hubble image relative to the center of M51 mapsthe galaxy&amp;rsquo;s spiral arms into diagonal straight lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Solar Eclipse Below the Bottom of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
In late 2021 there was a total solar eclipse visible only at the end of the Earth. To capture the , airplanes took flight below the clouded seascape of .The shows one relatively spectacular capture where the bright spot is the outer of the Sun and the is seen as the dark spot in the center. A wing and engine of the are visible across the left and bottom of the image, while is visible on the far left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galileo&#39;s Europa</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 09:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Looping through the Jovian system in the late 1990s, therecorded stunning views of Europa and uncoveredevidence that the moon&amp;rsquo;s icy surface likely hidesa deep, global ocean.Galileo&amp;rsquo;s Europa image data has been, with improved calibrations to produce acolor image approximating what the human eye might see.Europa&amp;rsquo;s long curving fractures. The tidal flexing the large moon experiencesin its elliptical orbitaround Jupiter supplies the energy to keep the ocean liquid.But more is the possibilitythat even in theabsence of sunlight that process could also supply the energy tosupport life,one of the best places to look for lifebeyond Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back at an Eclipsed Earth</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Mir 27 Crew
Here is what the Earth looks like during a.Theof the can be seen darkening part of.This moved the at nearly 2000 kilometers per hour.Only near the center of the see a total solar eclipse -others see a partial eclipse where only part of the.This of the 1999 August 11was one of the last evertaken from the .The two bright spots that appear on the upper left are thought to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ares 3 Landing Site The Martian Revisited</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 09:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: HiRISE
the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter&amp;rsquo;sHiRISE camera shows weathered craters and windblown deposits in southern.A striking shade of blue in standard HiRISE image colors,to the human eye the area would probably look grey or a little reddish.But human eyes have not gazedacross this terrain, unless you count the eyes of NASA astronautsin the scifi novel by Andy Weir.The novel chronicles the adventures of Mark Watney,an astronaut stranded at the fictional Mars mission Ares 3 landing sitecorresponding to the coordinates of this cropped HiRISE frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Picturesque Equinox Sunset</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Alan Dyer
What&amp;rsquo;s that at the end of the road?The Sun.Many towns have roads that run east-west, and on two days each year, the Sun rises and sets .Today, in some parts of the world (tomorrow in others), is one of those days: an . Not only is this a day of equal night and day time, but also a day when the precisely to the east and sets due west.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Full Plankton Moon</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
What glows in the night?This night a combination of usual and unusual glows.Perhaps the most usual glow was from, a potentially familiar object.The full Moon&amp;rsquo;s nearly results from the observer being near.As the Moon sets, ands in preferentially scatter out blue light, makingthe appear reddish whennear the horizon. Perhaps the mostwas from the bioluminescent, likely less familiar objects.These glow blue, it is thought, primarily toand.In this case, the glow was caused primarily byplankton-containing waves crashing onto the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Total Eclipse at the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:00:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Fred Bruenjes
Would you go to the end of the world to see a total eclipse of the Sun?If you did, would you be surprised to find someone else In 2003, the , the Moon, Antarctica, and two photographers all lined up in during an unusual. Even given the extreme location, a group of ventured near thebottom of the world to momentarydisappearance of the . One of the treasures collected was the &amp;ndash; a composite of four separate imagesdigitally combined to realistically simulate how the adaptive human the eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tarantula Zone</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:00:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Robert Gendler
,also known as 30 Doradus, is more than a thousand light-years in diameter,a giant star forming region within nearby satellite galaxy the.About 180 thousand light-years away, it&amp;rsquo;s the largest,most violent star forming region known in the whole LocalGroup of galaxies.The cosmic arachnid sprawls across,an assembly of image data from large space- and ground-based telescopes. (NGC 2070),intense radiation, stellar winds, and supernova shocksfrom the central young cluster of massive stars cataloged as R136energize the nebular glow and shape the spidery filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
