<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:00:18 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/tags/nasa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Picturesque Equinox Sunset</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Alan Dyer
What&amp;rsquo;s that at the end of the road?The Sun.Many towns have roads that run east-west, and on two days each year, the Sun rises and sets .Today, in some parts of the world (tomorrow in others), is one of those days: an . Not only is this a day of equal night and day time, but also a day when the precisely to the east and sets due west.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGC 7714 Starburst after Galaxy Collision</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Is this galaxy jumping through a ? Probably not. Although the precise the featured image is yet unclear, what is clear is that the pictured galaxy, , has been stretched and distorted by a recent collision with a neighboring galaxy.This smaller neighbor, , situated off to the left of the frame, is thought to have right through .Observations indicate that the golden is composed of millions of older Sun-like stars that are likely co-moving with the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Full Plankton Moon</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
What glows in the night?This night a combination of usual and unusual glows.Perhaps the most usual glow was from, a potentially familiar object.The full Moon&amp;rsquo;s nearly results from the observer being near.As the Moon sets, ands in preferentially scatter out blue light, makingthe appear reddish whennear the horizon. Perhaps the mostwas from the bioluminescent, likely less familiar objects.These glow blue, it is thought, primarily toand.In this case, the glow was caused primarily byplankton-containing waves crashing onto the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Total Eclipse at the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:00:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Fred Bruenjes
Would you go to the end of the world to see a total eclipse of the Sun?If you did, would you be surprised to find someone else In 2003, the , the Moon, Antarctica, and two photographers all lined up in during an unusual. Even given the extreme location, a group of ventured near thebottom of the world to momentarydisappearance of the . One of the treasures collected was the &amp;ndash; a composite of four separate imagesdigitally combined to realistically simulate how the adaptive human the eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tarantula Zone</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:00:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Robert Gendler
,also known as 30 Doradus, is more than a thousand light-years in diameter,a giant star forming region within nearby satellite galaxy the.About 180 thousand light-years away, it&amp;rsquo;s the largest,most violent star forming region known in the whole LocalGroup of galaxies.The cosmic arachnid sprawls across,an assembly of image data from large space- and ground-based telescopes. (NGC 2070),intense radiation, stellar winds, and supernova shocksfrom the central young cluster of massive stars cataloged as R136energize the nebular glow and shape the spidery filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
