<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/tags/nasa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nasa on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:00:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/tags/nasa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Comet Pons-Brooks in Northern Spring</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek&#xA;As spring approaches for northern skygazers,is growing brighter.with small telescopes and binoculars,the Halley-type comet could reach naked eye visibility in thecoming weeks.Seen despite a foggy atmosphere,the comet&amp;rsquo;s green coma and long tail hover near the horizonin this well-composedfrom Revuca, Slovakia recorded on March 5.In the sky above the comet,the Andromeda (right) and Triangulum galaxies,beta star of the constellation Andromeda.The two spiral galaxies are members of our local galaxy group andover 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tarantula Zone</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/roberto_colombari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:00:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/roberto_colombari/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Robert Gendler&#xA;,also known as 30 Doradus, is more than a thousand light-years in diameter,a giant star forming region within nearby satellite galaxy the.About 180 thousand light-years away, it&amp;rsquo;s the largest,most violent star forming region known in the whole LocalGroup of galaxies.The cosmic arachnid sprawls across,an assembly of image data from large space- and ground-based telescopes. (NGC 2070),intense radiation, stellar winds, and supernova shocksfrom the central young cluster of massive stars cataloged as R136energize the nebular glow and shape the spidery filaments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>M102 Edge-on Disk Galaxy</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 09:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/esa/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA&#xA;What kind of celestial object is this?A relatively normal galaxy &amp;ndash; but seen from its edge. Many disk galaxies are actually just as thin as NGC 5866, the Spindle galaxy, , but are not from our vantage point. A perhaps more familiar galaxy seen edge-on is our own . Also cataloged as M102, the has numerous and complex dust lanes appearing dark and red, while many of the bright stars in the disk give it a more blue underlying hue.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/en/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
