<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:58 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sperm whale pod surfacing, Dominica</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279258759_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279258759_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</guid>
      <description>Ahoy there, giants of the sea! World Whale Day is surfacing yet again, along with these sperm whales off the coast of the Caribbean island of Dominica. Established in 1980 in Maui, the day originally aimed to celebrate the humpback whales in Hawaiian waters and has evolved into a global event advocating for the conservation of all whale species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pragser Wildsee in the Dolomites, South Tyrol, Italy</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</guid>
      <description>The Pragser Wildsee, set among the majestic Dolomites, is an Alpine jewel also known as Lake Braies. Its crystal waters reflect the impressive peaks of the Dolomites, surrounded by green forests. Accessible via a scenic trail, the lake attracts visitors for hikes and walks during the mild seasons. In summer, it turns into a destination for relaxing boat rides, while in winter the landscape takes on unique magic. The Pragser Wildsee is a mix of natural beauty, history, and culture, with the little church of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>抹香鲸浮出水面，多米尼克</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</guid>
      <description>嗨，海中的巨人们！世界鲸鱼日与加勒比海多米尼克岛沿岸的抹香鲸一起再次浮出水面。这个节日于1980年在毛伊岛设立，最初是为了庆祝夏威夷水域的座头鲸，现在已经演变成一个倡导保护所有鲸鱼物种的全球性活动。</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
