<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home of Katheryn Fox on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home of Katheryn Fox on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>有志者事竟成</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jason_kaplan_2021050749497733/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 01:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jason_kaplan_2021050749497733/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Jason Kaplan
納森．米德（Nathan Meader）在尼克．布羅德（Nick Broeder）的繫繩協助之下，完成了這趟攀岩，他從中繼固定點垂降下來，然後兩人在此休息過夜。在我開始曝光攝影前，有另一個攀岩隊成功登頂然後回到地面，可以看出他們移動的路線。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>公車上</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_ryan_harding_2022012670543945/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:59:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_ryan_harding_2022012670543945/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Photograph by Ryan Harding
這張照片攝於臺北，是我的系列攝影作品之一。我想記錄臺灣的生活風景，藉由聚焦於各種日常中普羅大眾各種異乎尋常、率直自然的有趣行為，呈現出一種復古、神祕而有如夢境般的感覺。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toledo, Spain (© Carlos Fernandez/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tajoriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:46:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tajoriver/</guid>
      <description>Toledo, a city situated in the Castilla-La Mancha region of Spain, is known for its unique geography. Positioned on a raised mass of land, the city is embraced by the Tagus River on three sides. This splendid city was called &amp;lsquo;The City of Three Cultures&amp;rsquo; during the Middle Ages, where Christian, Muslim and Jewish communities coexisted harmoniously. Toledo has been a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 1986, and its historical core is packed with mosques, synagogues and an impressive Gothic cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lincoln Memorial, Washington, DC (© Steve Whiston/Fallen Log Photography/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lincolnsunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lincolnsunset/</guid>
      <description>The United States of America has had 46 commanders in chief, and today, the third Monday of February, we commemorate their legacies. Initially established to honor George Washington&amp;rsquo;s birthday, Presidents Day has evolved into a celebration of all presidents. Revered among them is Abraham Lincoln, a towering figure in American history, who guided the country through the Civil War and abolished slavery in America. The Lincoln Memorial, seen in today&amp;rsquo;s image, overlooks the Reflecting Pool at the west end of the National Mall in Washington, DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>乱れて咲くしだれ梅の花, 京都府 京都市 (© EvergreenPlanet/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ume2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:45:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ume2024/</guid>
      <description>梅の花が咲き誇る季節がやってきました。桜に先駆けて咲き始める寒さに負けないこの花は、春の訪れや忍耐などの象徴として古くから日本人に愛され、古典文学や俳句にもよく登場します…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>鸟瞰克鲁斯港色彩斑斓的房屋，特内里费岛，西班牙</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnavaltenerife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 17:34:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnavaltenerife/</guid>
      <description>这些色彩斑斓的街道之间发生了什么？想象下有这样一个地方，大西洋轻抚着色彩斑斓的海岸，泰德峰从3715米的高度俯瞰着它。这个地方就是特内里费岛，西班牙加那利群岛上一个风景秀美四季如春的天堂。但当二月来临时，这座岛屿就会焕然一新：这是独属于圣克鲁斯-德特内里费的狂欢节时间，其视觉效果和节日盛况可与著名的巴西里约热内卢狂欢节相媲美，也被认为是世界上第二热门和知名的狂欢节。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pragser Wildsee in the Dolomites, South Tyrol, Italy</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</guid>
      <description>The Pragser Wildsee, set among the majestic Dolomites, is an Alpine jewel also known as Lake Braies. Its crystal waters reflect the impressive peaks of the Dolomites, surrounded by green forests. Accessible via a scenic trail, the lake attracts visitors for hikes and walks during the mild seasons. In summer, it turns into a destination for relaxing boat rides, while in winter the landscape takes on unique magic. The Pragser Wildsee is a mix of natural beauty, history, and culture, with the little church of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>抹香鲸浮出水面，多米尼克</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</guid>
      <description>嗨，海中的巨人们！世界鲸鱼日与加勒比海多米尼克岛沿岸的抹香鲸一起再次浮出水面。这个节日于1980年在毛伊岛设立，最初是为了庆祝夏威夷水域的座头鲸，现在已经演变成一个倡导保护所有鲸鱼物种的全球性活动。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
https://github.com/yuin/goldmark https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>壁纸自助网站
Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
