<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home of Katheryn Fox on Blist Multilingual Theme</title>
    <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home of Katheryn Fox on Blist Multilingual Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alisonjoe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>南极洲冰山上的阿德利企鹅</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/penguindirections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 02:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/penguindirections/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Patrick J. Endres/Getty Images
可以滑行，又何需飞行？世界企鹅日快乐！这些不会飞的鸟主要栖息在南极洲，从帝企鹅到今天的明星阿德利企鹅，种类繁多。1840年，法国冒险家儒勒·杜蒙·德维尔发现了阿德利企鹅，并决定以他心爱的妻子的名字“阿德利”来命名这种企鹅。阿德利企鹅虽然体型娇小，但游泳动作敏捷，可以潜入575英尺深的海底寻找长得像虾一样的磷虾或鱼类。它们是社会性动物，会聚集在小群中觅食、狩猎和保护自己。调皮捣蛋的阿德利企鹅还会偷窃附近巢穴中的鹅卵石来加固自己的巢穴，以保护自己的蛋和雏鸟免受南极洲恶劣环境和捕食者的伤害。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painting titled &#39;Saint George and the Dragon&#39; by Paolo Uccello (© Photo 12/Universal Images Group via Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/saintgeorgepaolouccello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/saintgeorgepaolouccello/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Photo 12/Universal Images Group via Getty Images
Are you ready to wave your flags and celebrate all things English? Saint George&amp;rsquo;s Day has rolled around once again. Today is a commemoration the death of the patron saint of England who was a Roman soldier famed for his dragon-slaying. This feast day is not just about honouring the saint, it&amp;rsquo;s also about celebrating English culture and heritage. From dragon-themed parades in Derby to traditional feasts fit for a king, there&amp;rsquo;s something for everyone to enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>盛开的白延龄草，安大略省，加拿大</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/trilliumontario/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 02:00:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/trilliumontario/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Jun Zhang/Getty Images
三片花瓣、三片叶子和三个柱头——这就是白延龄草，它的名字源自拉丁语中的“三”，原产于北美东部，是春季最常见的林地野花之一。与一些稍有暖意就绽放色彩的“冲动型”花朵不同，这种植物开花缓慢。从美国邮票上的图案到俄亥俄州的州花，再到加拿大安大略省的官方象征，白延龄草扎根于各国文化。除了美观之外，白延龄草在草药界也有一席之地。所以，你在林间漫步时，请留意这种花卉珍品！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pueblo medieval de Albarracín al amanecer, Teruel, Aragón, España (© Domingo Leiva/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aragonday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 06:00:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aragonday/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Domingo Leiva/Getty Images
En el corazón de Teruel, se alza Albarracín, un pueblo medieval que despierta al amanecer arropado en historia y belleza. Con su población de poco más de mil habitantes, Albarracín se erige majestuoso en su dignidad: Monumento Nacional desde 1961, Medalla de Oro al mérito en las Bellas Artes (1996) y miembro honorario de Los Pueblos Más Bonitos de España.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>三一学院图书馆，都柏林，爱尔兰</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/trinitydublin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 02:00:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/trinitydublin/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Lukas Bischoff/Getty Images
在爱尔兰中心，在都柏林圣三一学院图书馆历史悠久的大厅里，卷轴和古籍低声诉说着久远的故事。今天，这些沉默的故事讲述者将大放异彩。世界图书日由联合国教科文组织于1995年设立，旨在提醒人们阅读、出版和版权的重要性。但为什么是4月23日呢？因为这一天是威廉·莎士比亚、米格尔·德·塞万提斯和其他几位文学巨匠共同的忌日！从每年在马里兰州肯辛顿举办的汇集众多作家、诗人和文学组织的街头庆祝活动，到世界各地许多国家向孩子们分发图书券，这一天在书页翻动的沙沙声中变得生机勃勃。有趣的是，联合国教科文组织每年都会推选一个城市为“世界图书之都”，被选中的城市将在被授予的一年中开展促进阅读的活动，今年当选是法国斯特拉斯堡。那么，你选好要读的书了吗？</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Marathon in London on April 23, 2017 (© CHRIS J RATCLIFFE/Stringer/AFP/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/londonmarathon2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/londonmarathon2017/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © CHRIS J RATCLIFFE/Stringer/AFP/Getty Images
Lace up those sneakers, channel your inner Mo Farah and get ready to join the ranks of marathon legends. This year, the London Marathon is back in its usual spring spot! This second-largest annual race in the United Kingdom will see runners from all walks (or runs) of life come together to tackle the ultimate challenge: 26.2 miles of pure grit and determination. Starting off at one of the three start lines (blue, green and red) between Greenwich and Blackheath, runners weave their way through the streets of the capital city, passing historic landmarks like Tower Bridge and Buckingham Palace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>绿海龟，圣地亚哥，加利福尼亚，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/earthdayturtle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/earthdayturtle/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ralph Pace/Minden Pictures
今天是“地球日”，一个专门为保护地球环境而设立的节日，旨在提高民众对于现有环境问题的认识。1969年，时任威斯康星州参议员的盖洛德·纳尔逊目睹了库亚霍加河着火和圣巴巴拉石油泄漏等事件，他认为世界需要一项环保倡议，于是埋下了设立“地球日”的种子。一年后，首届“地球日”活动举行。现在，“地球日”已经发展成为一年一度的活动，有超过193个国家的10亿多人参加。今年，这项活动的重点是塑料，因为塑料污染已经严重影响了陆地和海洋环境。许多物种，包括图片中的这只绿海龟，误将海洋中的塑料垃圾当作食物食用。并且，这些塑料垃圾还会带来缠绕风险，也有可能分解成微塑料。每年约有2500万吨塑料进入水生生态系统。因此，赶快行动起来吧！植树造林、清理海滩，倡导环境保护及可持续发展，为人类共同的家园贡献自己的一份力量。毕竟，没有第二个地球！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Îles Chausey, Normandie, France (© Tuul &amp; Bruno Morandi/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chauseyislands/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 06:01:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chauseyislands/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Tuul &amp;amp; Bruno Morandi/Getty Images
Les îles Chausey sont un archipel normand situé au nord de la baie du Mont-Saint-Michel, là où les vagues caressent le granit. Un archipel de rêve, où la mer, joueuse, dévoile à marée basse un labyrinthe d’îlots et de bancs de sable. La Grande Île, perle de cet ensemble, s’éveille sous les premiers rayons du soleil, baignée d’une lumière douce qui réchauffe ses maisons de pierre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blumenbeete mit Tulpen und anderen Frühlingsblumen im Rheinpark, Köln (© Elisabeth Schittenhelm/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cologneflowerbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 06:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cologneflowerbed/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Elisabeth Schittenhelm/Getty Images
Willkommen im Rheinpark, einer Oase im Herzen Kölns. Der am Rheinufer gelegene Park vereint Geschichte und Natur. Einst Schauplatz der Bundesgartenschau 1957, erstrahlt er auch heute noch in seiner ganzen Pracht. Im Frühjahr entfaltet sich hier ein wahres Blütenmeer, das Herz und Sinne verzaubert. Die duftenden Blumenbeete vor der Kulisse des majestätischen Rheins laden dazu ein, sich auf einer Bank niederzulassen und diese Insel der Ruhe inmitten der westfälischen Metropole zu genießen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cades Cove ，大雾山国家公园，田纳西州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cadescove/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 02:00:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cadescove/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Richard Bernabe/Shutterstock
随着美国国家公园周活动的开展，让我们一起去田纳西州的大雾山国家公园走走吧！该公园成立于1934年，占地面积超过522,419英亩。这座公园的大部分地区都被森林覆盖着，是1500种开花植物、952种藻类、65种哺乳动物和240多种鸟类的家园，大雾山国家公也因此成为了国际生物圈保护区。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mural de Eduardo Kobra ‘Povos Nativos dos 5 continentes’ (© Donatas Dabravolskas/Alamy)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/povoindigena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 06:00:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/povoindigena/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日出时分的大棱镜泉，美国怀俄明州黄石国家公园</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yellowstonegeyser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 02:00:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yellowstonegeyser/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © XIN WANG/Getty Images
准备好你的登山靴吧，因为美国国家公园周到了！美国各地最迷人的风景区已敞开大门，邀请大家免费拥抱大自然。在整个庆祝活动期间，美国国家公园管理局将组织各种活动，包括由护林员带领的参观活动、志愿者活动和教育研讨会。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palazzo dei Priori, Perugia, Italia (© Photo Beto/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/perugiapriori/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 06:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/perugiapriori/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布罗德加环，奥克尼岛，苏格兰</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/orkneystones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/orkneystones/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Paul Williams - FunkyStock/Getty Images
在苏格兰北部的奥克尼群岛的中心地带，有一个古老的谜团：布罗德加环。这个新石器时代的石圈是一种古老的圆形土方工程，可以追溯到公元前2500年到2000年之间，石圈的直径约为340英尺。该遗址位于两个湖泊之间的狭长地带，最初由60块石头组成，如今只剩下36块。该石圈的确切用途至今仍不得而知。为了进一步了解该遗址，一项名为“挖掘布罗德加环”的发掘项目于2008年启动，但该项目尚未取得任何结论性成果。1999年，包括布罗德加环在内的新石器时代的奥克尼中心地带被联合国教科文组织列为世界遗产。如果你计划去苏格兰旅行，不妨去布罗德加环逛逛。在这里，你不仅可以呼吸到清新的空气，还可以感受石圈的悠久历史。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Eclipse and Comets</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tsinghua_u./</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 09:00:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tsinghua_u./</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Lin Zixuan
Not one, but two comets appeared near the Sun during .The expected comet was , but it was disappointingly dimmer than many had hoped.However, relatively unknown in long duration camera exposures. was the 5008th comet identified on images taken by &amp;amp; &amp;rsquo;s Sun-orbiting . Likely much smaller, Comet SOHO-5008 was a sungrazer which as it passed too . The featured image is not only unusual for capturing during an eclipse, but one of the that a has been photographed from the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Château royal d&#39;Amboise dans la vallée de la Loire, France (© iStock/Getty Images Plus/StockPhotoAstur)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/monumentsday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/monumentsday/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © iStock/Getty Images Plus/StockPhotoAstur
La Journée internationale des monuments et des sites que nous célébrons aujourd’hui, nous rappelle l&amp;rsquo;importance de préserver notre patrimoine culturel, qu&amp;rsquo;il s&amp;rsquo;agisse d&amp;rsquo;une œuvre architecturale majestueuse ou d&amp;rsquo;une simple sculpture, tant qu&amp;rsquo;elle détient une valeur exceptionnelle d&amp;rsquo;un point de vue historique, artistique ou scientifique.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>中世纪城墙，阿维拉，西班牙</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/avilaspain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/avilaspain/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Scott Suriano/Getty Images
今天是一个具有纪念意义的日子：国际古迹遗址日。这一天也被称为“世界遗产日”，旨在强调保护文化遗产的重要性。从建筑物到雕塑，古迹可以是任何一样东西，只要它在历史、艺术或科学层面具有突出的价值。世界上有许多令人惊讶的古迹，例如秘鲁的马丘比丘和埃及的吉萨金字塔等，而今天的图片展示的是一个石头建筑，它是西班牙阿维拉中世纪城墙的其中一部分。这些碉堡修建于11世纪至14世纪，周长超8000英尺，最初的修建目的是保护城市，抵御外来者的进攻，如今这里成为了旅游圣地，游客们可以沿着城墙漫步，欣赏城市和周围乡村的美景。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filaments of the Vela Supernova Remnant</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/noirlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 09:01:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/noirlab/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: CTIO
The explosion is over, but the consequences continue. About eleven thousand years ago, a star in the constellation of could be seen to , creating a strange point of light briefly visible to humans living near the beginning of . The outer layers of the star crashed into the , driving a that is still visible today. The captures some of that filamentary and gigantic shock in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ram Mandir, Ayodhya, Uttar Pradesh (© Ritesh Shukla/Stringer/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ramanavami/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ramanavami/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ritesh Shukla/Stringer/Getty Images
Today we look up at the stunning structure of Ram Mandir at Ayodhya! The partially built Hindu temple is known as the birthplace of Lord Rama. The details of Rama&amp;rsquo;s birth are chronicled in ancient scriptures like the Ramayana and the Mahabharata. According to these texts, he was born to Queen Kausalya and King Dasharatha.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cigar Galaxy from Hubble and Webb</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 09:00:49 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/esa/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Something strange happened to this galaxy, but what?Known as the and cataloged as , red glowing gas and dust are being cast out from the center. Although this was surely stirred up by a recent pass near its , large spiral galaxy , this doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully explain the source of the red-glowing outwardly expanding gas and . Evidence indicates that this material is being driven out by the combined emerging of many stars, together creating a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>暮色中的曼哈顿下城联合广场，纽约，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/unionsquarenyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 02:00:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/unionsquarenyc/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Sean Pavone/Getty Images
“纵横交错的街道令人焕然一新，璀璨的霓虹灯让人热血沸腾。” 流行歌手艾丽西亚·凯斯在歌曲《帝国之心》中这样描述大苹果市（纽约的别称）的繁华与活力。今天，主页的图片将我们带到 “不夜城 ”的其中一个景点：曼哈顿下城的联合广场。在这个历史悠久的十字路口，您可以看到乔治·华盛顿的雕像，它是纽约市所有公园中最古老的雕像，以及雕塑家亨利·柯克·布朗创作的亚伯拉罕·林肯的雕像。1882年，工人们行使他们言论自由和集会自由的权利，在联合广场组织了第一次劳动节游行。正因如此，联合广场在美国劳工史上具有特殊的意义，1997年美国内政部将其认定为国家历史地标。时光飞逝，如今的曼哈顿更加繁华，当你漫步在街头，或许会在广场上看到街头棋手、音乐家、滑板爱好者、舞蹈团体和各类小贩。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>アントワープ中央駅, ベルギー (© Brit Worgan/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/redballbelgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 06:11:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/redballbelgium/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Brit Worgan/Getty Images
今日 4 月 15 日は世界芸術の日であり、「モナ・リザ」などの名作で知られるルネサンスの巨匠、レオナルド・ダ・ヴィンチの誕生日でもあります。世界芸術の日をお祝いして、ベルギーのアントワープ中央駅で展示されたアート作品、レッドボール・プロジェクトをお届けします…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bailadoras en la Feria de Sevilla, España (© Pepitoko/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/feriadesevilla/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:03:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/feriadesevilla/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Pepitoko/Getty Images
Cuando la primavera despierta en Andalucía, el alma de Sevilla se engalana para celebrar su icónica Feria de Abril. El Real de la Feria se transforma en una pintoresca ciudad donde el olor a azahar se mezcla con el sonido de las palmas y el taconeo. Una marea de colores y, hasta más de medio millón de visitantes, inunda las calles junto a las bailaoras, cuyos vestidos de volantes danzan al compás de las sevillanas, luciendo sus mejores trajes de flamenca.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerisiers en fleur, parc Queen Elizabeth, Vancouver, Canada (© Yun Han Xu/Moment Open/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sakuradaysjapanfair/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:02:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sakuradaysjapanfair/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Yun Han Xu/Moment Open/Getty Images
Alors que le printemps colore Vancouver, le parc Queen Elizabeth offre un spectacle captivant avec ses cerisiers en fleur. Imaginez-vous marcher sous leurs pétales délicats qui flottent comme des confettis. Autrefois une carrière de basalte, le parc a été transformé dans les années 1930 et inauguré par le roi George VI et la reine Elizabeth en 1939. Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, il est un pôle culturel avec des sculptures, des sentiers de promenade, une serre et des installations récréatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alone solare sulle Dolomiti presso il lago di Antermoia, Italia (© Walter Donega/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/alonesole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:02:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/alonesole/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grand National at Aintree Racecourse, England (© Tim Goode/Pool/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/grandnationaldayuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:01:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/grandnationaldayuk/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Tim Goode/Pool/Getty Images
The Grand National is back in the saddle for another thrilling ride. Scheduled to take place at Aintree Racecourse, the event will see 34 runners tackling 30 fences around 4 1/4 miles for the glory. This annual National Hunt horse race was first run in 1839. From steeplechaser Red Rum&amp;rsquo;s record-breaking triumphs to heart-stopping photo finishes, the Grand National has provided countless memorable moments for nearly two centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stängellose Schlüsselblumen, Weener, Niedersachsen (© Mohssen Assanimoghaddam/picture alliance via Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/weenerprimroses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/weenerprimroses/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Mohssen Assanimoghaddam/picture alliance via Getty Images
In den sanften Auen von Weener, einem malerischen Städtchen in Niedersachsen, tanzen die Stängellosen Schlüsselblumen im Frühlingswind. Welche Freude für Augen, Herz und Seele, endlich wieder Blumen, Farben und Licht zu sehen. Der kalte Winter liegt nun hinter uns und ist nur noch ein vergangener Traum, der Tag für Tag von uns weicht. Die Natur blüht auf, wie diese Blume, auch Primel genannt, die den Frühling ankündigt und unsere Umgebung in einen Garten Eden verwandelt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>保龄球海滩的日落，门多西诺县，加利福尼亚，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bowlingballcali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 02:03:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bowlingballcali/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Melo Qiao/Getty Images
欢迎来到大自然的保龄球馆！位于加州门多西诺海岸的保龄球海滩以散布在海岸上的那些引人注目的岩石而命名。这些砂岩球（一种被称为结核的现象）是在数百万年的沉积过程中形成的，沉积层围绕着由矿物胶结物固定在一起的砂石核心堆积而成。侵蚀作用逐渐磨损了外层，露出我们今天看到的球形。这创造了一个只有在退潮时才会出现的迷人景象。这种砂岩球很罕见，人们对它们的来源有很多疯狂的猜测，有人认为它们是外星碎片，也有人怀疑它们是恐龙化石。然而，答案非常简单：这是大自然的力量在起作用。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vue nocturne depuis le Rhône sur la ville de Lyon avec le Grand Hôtel-Dieu et la cathédrale de Fourvière, France (© Frédéric Prochasson/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lyongastronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 06:01:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lyongastronomy/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Frédéric Prochasson/Getty Images
La Fête de la Gastronomie est un rendez-vous annuel qui célèbre la richesse et la diversité de la cuisine française. C&amp;rsquo;est une opportunité pour les passionnés de bonne cuisine de découvrir de délicieux mets, de participer à des événements culinaires et de célébrer l&amp;rsquo;art culinaire sous toutes ses formes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jardim botânico de Curitiba, Paraná (© Marcelo Araujo/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/curitiba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 06:01:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/curitiba/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>富士本栖湖リゾート, 山梨県 (© Torsakarin/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/shibazakura2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 06:00:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/shibazakura2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Torsakarin/Getty Images
今日から山梨、富士本栖湖リゾートで、｢富士芝桜まつり｣がスタートします。富士山の麓に広がる広大な敷地には、ピンクや白など色とりどりの約 50 万株のシバザクラが絨毯のように咲き誇っています。その規模は関東最大級を誇り、毎年全国各地から訪れた多くの観光客で賑わいます…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>拱门国家公园，犹他州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sunsetarchesnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 02:00:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sunsetarchesnp/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Anthony Heflin/Shutterstock
如果你想沉浸式感受在时光中漫步的滋味，拱门国家公园是一个绝佳的选择！该公园拥有2000多座天然石拱，数百座高大的尖塔、大型石鳍和巨大的平衡石，是世界上风景最优美的旅游胜地之一。在两平方英里左右的空间内囊括了不少壮丽景观，包括北窗拱门（最具人气的巨环之一），炮塔拱门和双拱门。而以伊甸园、大象丘（5653英尺高）和大象巡游等名字命名的景点对游客而言，则意味着这里永远不缺壮观的景色。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planets Around a Total Eclipse</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 09:00:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nuits_sacr%C3%A9es/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Stéphane Vetter
What wonders appear when the Moon blocks the Sun?For many eager observers of of the Sun, the suddenly dark sky included the expected corona and two (perhaps surprise) planets: .Normally, in recent days, Venus is visible only in the morning when the Sun and Jupiter are below the horizon, while Jupiter appears bright only in the evening. On Monday, though, for well-placed observers, both planets became easily visible during the day right in line with the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Muslims gather to offer prayers during Eid al-Fitr at Jama Masjid in New Delhi (© MONEY SHARMA/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eidprayers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eidprayers/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © MONEY SHARMA/Getty Images
Rise and shine, it&amp;rsquo;s Eid al-Fitr! Pictured here is the spiritual submission of devotees at Jama Masjid, Delhi. A festival observed by Muslims worldwide, Eid al-Fitr marks the completion of the month-long fasting period of Ramadan. Ramadan holds profound significance in the Muslim religion, as it serves as a time of introspection and spiritual growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massif montagneux de Whistler, Colombie-Britannique, Canada (© Insight Photography/Design Pics/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/whistlerwssf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 06:01:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/whistlerwssf/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Insight Photography/Design Pics/Getty Images
Préparez-vous à dévaler les pistes! Whistler ne se contente pas d&amp;rsquo;être une simple montagne, c&amp;rsquo;est une station de ski renommée. Depuis sa création en 1996 par Dough Perry, un skieur et entraîneur expérimenté, le Festival mondial du ski et du snowboard (WSSF) attire les amateurs d&amp;rsquo;adrénaline. Au fil des ans, cee évènement est devenu le plus grand festival annuel de sports d&amp;rsquo;hiver et de musique d’Amérique du Nord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aerial view of Churun-Meru (Dragon) waterfall, Venezuela (© AirPano LLC/Amazing Aerial Agency)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/dragonwaterfall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 06:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/dragonwaterfall/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © AirPano LLC/Amazing Aerial Agency
In the heart of the wilderness, an awe-inspiring sight plummets from a mountain—the Churún Merú waterfall in Venezuela! Also known as Dragon Falls, the cascade featured in today&amp;rsquo;s image is in a narrow niche at the southern end of the canyon that divides the mountain of Auyan Tepui. Falling from around 396 metres, Churún Merú is joined by a neighboring stream in the wet season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American black bear cub in spring, Shenandoah National Park, Virginia (© Scott Suriano/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springcub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 06:02:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springcub/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Scott Suriano/Getty Images
Welcome to the world, bear cub! After spending the first months of its life inside the den, this frizzy American black bear child may be puzzled by the outside world. The cubs are born between January and February, but they don&amp;rsquo;t leave their den until about mid-April or the beginning of May. When the young bears emerge into spring, they weigh around 2 kilograms and grow to about 35 kilograms by their first birthday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dune di sale nelle saline, Sardegna, Italia (© Stefano Oppo/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sardiniasalt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 06:01:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sardiniasalt/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vista aérea da cidade de Cuiabá e do rio Cuiabá, Mato Grosso (© Lucas Ninno/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cuiabaaniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 06:01:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cuiabaaniversary/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Llansteffan Castle, Carmarthenshire, Wales (© Roy Shakespeare/Loop Images Ltd/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/llansteffancastlewales/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 06:01:24 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/llansteffancastlewales/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Roy Shakespeare/Loop Images Ltd/Alamy Stock Photo
In the heart of Carmarthenshire, Wales, near the River Tywi estuary, stands Llansteffan Castle. This historical gem dates to the 12th century when the Normans decided to mark their territory in this strategic spot. With sweeping views over the estuary and the countryside, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to see why they chose this location. The castle served as a focal point in the tug-of-war between the Normans and the native Welsh princes, witnessing numerous battles and sieges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total solar eclipse photographed from Madras, Oregon on August 21, 2017 (© NASA/Aubrey Gemignani)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/solareclipseoregon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 06:01:10 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/solareclipseoregon/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © NASA/Aubrey Gemignani
Put on your solar glasses and turn your eyes skyward. Today, you can witness a rare celestial event—a total solar eclipse! As the moon perfectly aligns between the Earth and the sun, daytime will eerily shift to twilight. The total solar eclipse will be visible across North America, from Mazatlán, Mexico, to eastern Canada&amp;rsquo;s Newfoundland Island, for up to four and a half minutes between 10:57 am PST and 4:47 pm ADT A total solar eclipse occurs somewhere on Earth approximately every 18 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>郁金香田，斯卡吉特山谷，华盛顿州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/skagitvalleytulips/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 02:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/skagitvalleytulips/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Claudia Cooper/Getty Images
在弗农山的阴影下，鲜艳的花朵为大地涂上一层色彩，造就了一幅真实的画卷，华盛顿斯卡吉特山谷的郁金香节正在等你。郁金香节于1984年由弗农山商会创办，最初的活动为期三天，后来发展成为为期一个月的盛会。节日从四月持续到五月，吸引了来自世界各地的游客。花展横跨山谷中的多个花园，千万不要错过郁金香镇、郁金香谷农场、罗莎琳花园以及鲁森加德占地50英亩的花展，你可以骑自行车游览郁金香花园，还可以探索当地的酒庄、酿酒厂和餐馆。漫步花间，生活放慢了脚步，让我们记住简单的快乐：深呼吸，绽放笑容，沉醉在斯卡吉特山谷郁金香节的美景中。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burrowing owl chicks near a burrow, Wyoming (© Danita Delimont/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/owlsiblings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:00:53 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/owlsiblings/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Danita Delimont/Getty Images
In today&amp;rsquo;s image, we see four burrowing owls in Wyoming, USA, standing near their burrow, looking like a band of mischievous siblings. Known for their distinctive white eyebrows and yellow eyes, these owls are active during the day, hunting insects and small mammals. These resilient species, capable of surviving for at least 9 years in the wild and surpassing 10 years in captivity, face numerous threats in their environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>リンゴの果樹園, ドイツ (© Smileus/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springapple/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Smileus/Getty Images
ここはドイツのとある果樹園。リンゴの木が暖かな春の光を浴びて目覚めを迎え、枝から小さな緑の芽が顔を出し始めます。その後、美しい白や淡いピンク色の花が咲き誇り、やがて美味しい果実へと姿を変えていきます…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>欧洲刺猬在长满蒲公英的花园里，巴特德里堡，德国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hedgehogmeadow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hedgehogmeadow/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Oksana Schmidt/Getty Images
欧洲刺猬，又称西欧刺猬或普通刺猬，是一种原产于欧洲的刺猬物种。北起伊比利亚和意大利，南至斯堪的纳维亚半岛，西至不列颠群岛，均有它们的身影。刺猬之中，偶尔会出现白化刺猬或“金发”刺猬，据说这种刺猬有一对罕见的隐性基因，因此眼睛是黑色的，刺是乳白色的，但严格来说，它们并不是白化刺猬。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unwinding M51</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 09:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/paul_howell/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Hubble Heritage Project
The arms of a grand design spiral galaxy 60,000 light-years across areunwound in this digital transformation of the magnificent 2005.In fact, M51 is one of the original spiral nebulae, its windingarms described by a mathematical curve known as a, a spiral whose separation grows in away with increasing distance from the center.Applying logarithms to shift the pixelcoordinates in the Hubble image relative to the center of M51 mapsthe galaxy&amp;rsquo;s spiral arms into diagonal straight lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>奇迹湖附近池塘里的北美海狸，德纳里国家公园，阿拉斯加州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/beaverdenali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/beaverdenali/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Paul Souders/Getty Images
海狸被称为大自然的工程师，数百万年来一直在改造着世界。历史上，北美海狸曾面临来自人类的挑战。人们为了它们的皮毛而猎杀它们，它们“讨厌的”淡水栖息地也被摧毁了。然而，近年来，这些长着獠牙、有着桨尾的水坝建造者正在重新赢得尊重。这些动物不仅对水质有益，而且对陆地也有好处。海狸用它们富含铁元素的橙色门牙砍伐树木，辛勤地建造家园和栖息地。它们的水坝为无数物种创造了维持生命的湿地。与此同时，它们的巢穴既安全又舒适，入口处被战略性地淹没在水下，以阻止捕食者进入，并保障自己的隐私安全。作为啮齿类动物的海狸可以憋气长达15分钟，所以他们可以毫不费力地进入自己的水下巢穴。因此，让我们在国际海狸日向这些动物致敬吧！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pont del Bisbe, Barrio Gótico de Barcelona, España (© Alexander Spatari/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/neogothicbarcelona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/neogothicbarcelona/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Alexander Spatari/Getty Images
¿Has sentido alguna vez la magia que envuelve las calles del Barrio Gótico de Barcelona? Entre sus rincones ancestrales, se erige el Pont del Bisbe, este puente, que conecta el Palau de la Generalitat con la Casa dels Canonges, parece haber sido transportado desde la época medieval a nuestra era, aunque su nacimiento data de 1928, obra de Joan Rubió i Bellver, discípulo del genial Gaudí.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>姬路城，姫路，兵库县，日本</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/japanhimeji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 02:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/japanhimeji/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Julian Elliott Photography/Getty Images
从“草莓日”到“猫日”，甚至“蔬菜日”，日本有一系列“谐音节日”，这些节日都来源于駄洒落（一种用读音相同或相近的词汇来玩乐的日本文字游戏，与英语中的双关语类似）。今天的日期是4月6日，而日语中的“shiro”（城堡）这个词恰好是由“shi”（4）和“ro”（6）组成的。因此，这一天就成为了庆祝城堡的日子。还有什么比城堡日更好的机会来了解日本最大、游客最多的城堡——姬路城呢？它的历史可以追溯到1333年，是联合国教科文组织认定的世界遗产，拥有先进的防御设计和五个国宝级建筑。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>从国际空间站拍摄的巴哈马群岛</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bahamasspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 02:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bahamasspace/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © NASA
欢迎来到巴哈马，这里有碧蓝的海水、生机勃勃的珊瑚礁、露天餐饮和海盗的传说！这片西印度群岛位于大西洋，拥有3000多个岛礁，是世界第三大堡礁安德罗斯堡礁的所在地。贾卡努狂欢节是该国的国家级文化节，创意表达在节日游行中占据了中心位置，人们会展示服装、传统音乐、手工艺以及讲故事。每年的节礼日和元旦也会举行庆祝活动。对于热爱大自然的冒险家来说，663英尺深的长岛迪恩斯蓝洞将为您带来刺激的体验。从海港岛宁静的粉色沙滩到首都拿骚那繁华的稻草市场和著名的酒窖，巴哈马不仅是一个旅游胜地，还是一个静待人们探索的迷人故事。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newcastle Upon Tyne, England (© Allan Baxter/The Image Bank/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/newcastleupontyneuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 06:01:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/newcastleupontyneuk/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Allan Baxter/The Image Bank/Getty Images
Nestled on the banks of the River Tyne, Newcastle Upon Tyne&amp;rsquo;s story is one of transformation. Amongst its cobbled streets and historic buildings lies a treasure trove of tales. The city started life as Pons Aelius, a Roman settlement. It was on this site that the Norman fortress that gave the city its name was built. During the Middle Ages, the city was an important trading power, while during Victorian age, its shipbuilding and engineering works made Newcastle a vital part of the Industrial Revolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Îles Broken Group, réserve de parc national Pacific Rim, île de Vancouver, Colombie-Britannique (© Ron Watts/Design Pics/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/pacificrimnationalpark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 06:01:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/pacificrimnationalpark/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ron Watts/Design Pics/Getty Images
Partons à la découverte du parc national Pacific Rim sur l&amp;rsquo;île de Vancouver, où les forêts pluviales se mêlent aux côtes rocheuses dans un paysage époustouflant. Ce parc de 511 km², établi en 1970, est le territoire ancestral des Premières Nations Nuu-chah-nulth. Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, plusieurs tribus Nuu-chah-nulth y possèdent des réserves. La région est également renommée pour sa forêt de pruches et la diversité de la faune, comprenant notamment des ours noirs, des couguars et des martres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpe di Siusi, Dolomiti, Italia (© Achim Thomae/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/dolomitesseiseralm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 06:01:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/dolomitesseiseralm/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>吉野山の桜, 奈良県 吉野郡 (© Sean Pavone/iStock/Getty Images Plus)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yoshinoyamaspring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 06:01:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yoshinoyamaspring/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Sean Pavone/iStock/Getty Images Plus
今日 4 月 4 日は二十四節気の「清明」。中国では清明節という祝日で、先祖の墓参りの風習があります。また、「清明」は万物が清々しく明るく美しいことを指し、様々な花が咲き乱れ、お花見シーズンの到来時期です…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Château de Chambord, Vallée de la Loire, France (© Susanne Kremer/Huber/eStock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chambordcastle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:00:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chambordcastle/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Susanne Kremer/Huber/eStock Photo
Connaissez-vous le Château de Chambord ? Ce monument est une perle de la Renaissance française, inspirée par François Ier et Léonard de Vinci. Bien que l&amp;rsquo;architecte demeure inconnu, l&amp;rsquo;influence de Vinci se reflète dans chaque pierre de ce joyau. Après la bataille de Marignan en 1515, François Ier, inspiré par les splendeurs de l&amp;rsquo;architecture italienne et les talents de Vinci, l&amp;rsquo;invite à rejoindre sa cour en tant qu&amp;rsquo;artiste et ingénieur en chef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tea plantation near Munnar, Kerala (© Peter Zelei Images/Moment/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/teaplantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/teaplantation/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Peter Zelei Images/Moment/Getty Images
Embark on a sensory journey through Munnar&amp;rsquo;s famed tea plantations! Situated amid the misty heights of the Western Ghats Mountain range, Munnar is a hill station and town in the Idukki district of Kerala. At approximately 1,600 metres above sea level, the town boasts a landscape characterised by rolling hills, lush valleys and verdant tea plantations. In the 1880s, European settlers established the first tea plantations in the region, marking the beginning of a flourishing industry that would shape the landscape and economy for decades to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At-Bashy地区的彩虹，Kakshaal Too山脉，纳伦省，吉尔吉斯斯坦</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/kyrgyzstanrainbow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 02:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/kyrgyzstanrainbow/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Emad aljumah/Getty Images
正如青蛙科米特（《布偶电影》中的主角）曾在歌曲《彩虹般的连接》中所唱的那样：“彩虹是幻象，但只是幻象，彩虹没有什么可以隐藏的……”每年4月3日是美国的 “全国寻找彩虹日”，这一天旨在庆祝这一多彩的自然现象，它让世界各地的人们都欣喜不已。当阳光通过大气中的雨滴，光线被反射和散射时，彩虹就会出现。在“寻找彩虹日”这天，人们会参加相关的活动，例如在雨后寻找彩虹或者是创作以彩虹为主题的艺术。在今天的图片中，我们看到一道彩虹挂在吉尔吉斯斯坦雄伟的Kakshaal Too 山脉上，崎岖的山峰和纯净原始的山谷构成了一副绝美的背景图，与稍纵即逝的彩虹美景相得益彰。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日德兰半岛的山毛榉树和野生海葵 ，丹麦</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jutlandspring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 02:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jutlandspring/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Nick Brundle Photography/Getty Images
今天，图片上的风景将我们带到了丹麦的日德兰半岛。随着春天的到来，这片北方的土地展现出了一种属于山毛榉树的绿色色调，而山毛榉树正是丹麦的“国树”。对于丹麦人民来说，这些正在发芽的山毛榉树是一种独特的存在，在四五月份，他们会把树上的嫩叶采摘下来用于烹饪中，尤其是用在沙拉中。过去，欧洲人经常使用山毛榉树光滑的树皮来书写文字。这也是为什么，在现代荷兰语中，&amp;ldquo;书籍&amp;quot;一词直接翻译为&amp;quot;山毛榉树&amp;rdquo;。当阳光穿过森林中的树冠照耀下来时，野生海葵用白色的花瓣点亮了林地，它们代表着精致之美和真诚纯粹，曾在莫奈和梵高等艺术家的杰作中“担任主角”。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Total Solar Eclipse Below the Bottom of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 09:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/eso/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
In late 2021 there was a total solar eclipse visible only at the end of the Earth. To capture the , airplanes took flight below the clouded seascape of .The shows one relatively spectacular capture where the bright spot is the outer of the Sun and the is seen as the dark spot in the center. A wing and engine of the are visible across the left and bottom of the image, while is visible on the far left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traunsteiner Pferde beim traditionellen St. Georgi-Ritt am Ostermontag in bayerischen Farben geschmückt, Deutschland (© Christof Stache/AFP via Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/stgeorgiride/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/stgeorgiride/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Christof Stache/AFP via Getty Images
Seit fast einem halben Jahrtausend treffen sich alljährlich am Ostermontag Reiter und Pilger zur traditionellen Pferdewallfahrt, dem Georgiritt. Dort kommen Menschen zusammen, die in einem Festzug mit Pferden und Kutschen zum Ettendorfer Kircherl bei Traunstein in Oberbayern pilgern. Geschmückte Reiter in prächtigen Trachten ziehen, begleitet von festlicher Musik, durch die malerische Landschaft Süddeutschlands vor der zauberhaften Kulisse der Alpen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>カラフルにペイントされたイースターエッグ, ハンガリー (© ATTILA KISBENEDEK/AFP/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hungarianeggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 06:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hungarianeggs/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © ATTILA KISBENEDEK/AFP/Getty Images
今日 3 月 31 日は復活祭。イエス・キリストの復活を祝う祭りで、キリスト教における最も重要な行事とされています。この復活祭を祝うために、ハンガリーのアーティストが創造した素敵な「イースターエッグ」をお届けします…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>„Vanishing Point“, des Straßenkünstlers JR bedeckt die Fassade des Palazzo Farnese, Rom, Italien (© Fabrizio Troiani/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/palazzofarnese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 06:00:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/palazzofarnese/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Fabrizio Troiani/Alamy Stock Photo
Im Herzen der italienischen Hauptstadt Rom befindet sich dieser prächtige Renaissancebau, der Palazzo Farnese. Es ist schwer zu sagen, welches das bedeutendste architektonische Denkmal Roms ist, oder? Der Palazzo wurde im 16. Jahrhundert für die mächtige und einflussreiche Familie Farnese erbaut und beeindruckt durch seine imposante Fassade und seine prachtvollen Innenräume. Heute beherbergt er die französische Botschaft in Italien und ist nur teilweise für die Öffentlichkeit zugänglich.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galileo&#39;s Europa</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 09:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jpl-caltech/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: NASA
Looping through the Jovian system in the late 1990s, therecorded stunning views of Europa and uncoveredevidence that the moon&amp;rsquo;s icy surface likely hidesa deep, global ocean.Galileo&amp;rsquo;s Europa image data has been, with improved calibrations to produce acolor image approximating what the human eye might see.Europa&amp;rsquo;s long curving fractures. The tidal flexing the large moon experiencesin its elliptical orbitaround Jupiter supplies the energy to keep the ocean liquid.But more is the possibilitythat even in theabsence of sunlight that process could also supply the energy tosupport life,one of the best places to look for lifebeyond Earth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Igreja do Nosso Senhor do Bonfim, Pelourinho (© Grafissimo/Getty images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aniversariosalvador/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/aniversariosalvador/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>睡在号角树上的褐喉树懒，哥斯达黎加</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sleepysloth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 02:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sleepysloth/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Juan Carlos Vindas/Getty Images
哥斯达黎加郁郁葱葱的森林是两种树懒的栖息地：霍夫曼双趾树懒和今天的主角——褐喉树懒。尽管褐喉树懒的体型比许多树栖哺乳动物都要大，但它们为了适应树上的生活，减少了肌肉含量，缩小了体型。它们的胃很大，有四个胃室，吃饱后可占体重的30%。这些毛茸茸的小动物久坐不动，以至于它们的皮毛上长出了藻类。这种共生关系为它们加入了绿色元素，在雨林树冠中提供了有效的伪装。2021年，这些行动缓慢的生物被宣布为哥斯达黎加的国家象征。为了强调树懒在该国生态系统中的重要性，卡洛斯·阿尔瓦拉多总统还签署了这项倡议，使其变成了法律条文。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日落时的南斯塔克灯塔，霍利希德，威尔士，英国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/southstacklight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 02:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/southstacklight/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © mariotlr/Getty Images
南斯塔克灯塔建在威尔士圣岛崎岖的悬崖上，俯瞰着爱尔兰海的深水区。自1809年建成以来，这座91英尺高的白塔一直为水手们指引方向；它为都柏林-霍利黑德-利物浦航线上的船只提供了安全通道。灯塔建成时，使用抹香鲸油点亮灯具；但多年来，灯塔的机械装置已升级为更先进的技术，如LED灯泡和菲涅尔透镜。灯塔于1984年实现自动化，其强大的光束照射范围可达28英里，至今仍是重要的导航设备。当夕阳西下，天空布满五彩斑斓的色彩时，南斯塔克灯塔在黄昏中的剪影令人叹为观止。游客们会勇敢地从陡峭的悬崖上爬下400级台阶，探索灯塔以及它的机房和展览区。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>上海的樱花，中国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/shanghaiblossoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 02:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/shanghaiblossoms/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Yaorusheng/Getty Images
春天，大自然展现出勃勃生机，樱花盛开标志着一个季节的开始。在全球范围内，从日本到美国，这一奇观吸引了数百万人的目光。在中国，樱花从3月下旬开到4月下旬，粉色和白色的樱花点缀着一幅幅美景。这些脆弱的花瓣在中国人的传统中有着深远的意义，象征着新生、希望和生命的短暂。中国有很多赏樱地点，包括武汉的东湖樱花公园、上海的顾村公园和鲁迅公园，以及北京的玉渊潭公园。樱花看起来与梅花相似，但区分两者的一个简单方法是看它们的花瓣。樱花的花瓣末端有分叉，而梅花没有。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An evening at the Amber Fort, near Jaipur, India (© Amith Nag Photography/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/amerfortjaipur/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 06:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/amerfortjaipur/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Amith Nag Photography/Getty Images
Hold on to your turbans, folks! We&amp;rsquo;re stepping into the realm of Amber! Atop a hill, overlooking the Maota Lake, lies the Amber Fort in the town of Amer, just 11 kilometres from Jaipur, Rajasthan. Amber, initially a Meena state governed by the Susawat clan, became the capital of Dhundhar after Kakil Deo defeated the Susawats. Later, Dulha Rai, a Kachhwaha prince, established Kachwaha dominance over Dhundhar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expo Business Center, Milano, Italia (© photovideostock/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/milanbusinesscenter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/milanbusinesscenter/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布宜诺斯艾利斯哥伦布剧院，阿根廷</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/teatrocolon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 02:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/teatrocolon/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Wei Hao Ho/Alamy Stock Photo
今天，整个世界都是一个大舞台。每年的3月27日，世界戏剧日都会在雷鸣般的掌声中拉开帷幕，为戏剧这个数百年来一直影响着大众的艺术形式奏响颂歌。世界戏剧日旨在推广戏剧，引起人们对戏剧艺术的重视，共享戏剧艺术给人类带来的精神财富。今天图中所见的是布宜诺斯艾利斯的哥伦布剧院，它是阿根廷丰富戏剧遗产的象征。这座剧院建于1908年，以其宏伟的建筑和卓越的音响效果而闻名，是世界上首屈一指的歌剧院。多年来，这里举办了许多传奇人物的演出，如恩里科·卡鲁索、理查·施特劳斯、莉丽·庞斯、玛丽娜·德·加巴林、乔斯·史东、布兰福德·马萨利斯等。在这个专属于戏剧的日子里，让我们一起欣赏这种以最壮观的方式讲述故事的艺术形式！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Une biche dans un champ de colza, lac de Serre-Ponçon, Chorges, Hautes-Alpes, France (© Alain Bachellier/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/procrastinationday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 06:00:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/procrastinationday/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Alain Bachellier/Getty Images
Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, en cette Journée Mondiale de la Procrastination, prenons un moment pour contempler la beauté tranquille qui nous entoure. Imaginez-vous cette biche se promenant dans un champ de colza doré, prenant son temps pour savourer chaque instant. Tout comme cet animal, parfois, nous avons besoin de ralentir et de prendre du recul. La procrastination peut être un moment de pause bien nécessaire dans nos vies trépidantes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>目黒川沿いの桜, 東京 (© twomeows/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cherryblossom2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cherryblossom2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © twomeows/Getty Images
明日 3 月 27 日は｢さくらの日｣。日本さくらの会が制定した桜の記念日です。また今の時期は七十二候の「桜始開」の時期で、暦の上では桜が開き始めるころと言われています…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>海水从古老的珊瑚礁上倾泻而下，杭莱，越南</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hangraivietnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 02:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hangraivietnam/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Thang Tat Nguyen/Getty Images
欢迎来到杭莱，这里既有古老的岩层，又有生机勃勃的珊瑚礁！这个洞穴也被称为獭洞，被努伊蔡国家公园包围着，是越南中南部海岸地区永希湾的一部分。该地区的天然珊瑚礁被岩层环绕，这些岩层堆叠在一起，形成了一组洞穴。“杭莱”或“獭洞”名称的由来之一，是人们偶尔会看到水獭在洞穴中栖息。另一种解释是由于该地区盛产莱树，这种树的油可以用于船只防水。无论是水下还是水上，这里都有令人惊叹的景观：深潜者可以观赏五颜六色的珊瑚，喜欢在海风中露营的游客可以欣赏美丽的日落。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back at an Eclipsed Earth</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cnes/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Mir 27 Crew
Here is what the Earth looks like during a.Theof the can be seen darkening part of.This moved the at nearly 2000 kilometers per hour.Only near the center of the see a total solar eclipse -others see a partial eclipse where only part of the.This of the 1999 August 11was one of the last evertaken from the .The two bright spots that appear on the upper left are thought to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blick auf Felder, Luftaufnahme, Bayern (© Westend61 GmbH/Alamy)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/viewfieldsbavaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:00:55 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/viewfieldsbavaria/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Westend61 GmbH/Alamy
Der Frühling ist da und die Natur erwacht zu neuem Leben. Schauen Sie sich diese Felder an. Zarte Grüntöne tanzen über die weiten Flächen, das sanfte Gelb der aufblühenden Blumen durchzieht die Landschaft. Ein Hauch von Lila verleiht dem Panorama eine magische Note, wenn sich die ersten Blüten gen Himmel strecken. Die Felder breiten sich wie ein Ozean aus Farben und Texturen vor einem aus, ein lebendiges Gemälde, das nicht nur Maler wie Vincent van Gogh, Claude Monet oder Emil Nolde, sondern auch Dichter wie Hermann Hesse, Joseph von Eichendorff und Friedrich Hölderlin inspiriert hat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>カラフルな色粉を投げ合う様子, インド (© Avishek Das/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/colorfulholi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 06:00:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/colorfulholi/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Avishek Das/SOPA Images/LightRocket via Getty Images
ホーリー祭は、インドやネパールの春祭りですが、バングラデシュ、パキスタン、イギリス、米国、スリナム、インドネシア、マレーシアなど、ヒンドゥー教徒の多い他の国々でも祝われています。通常 3 月の満月の日から始まり、2 日間にわたって行われます…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ares 3 Landing Site The Martian Revisited</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 09:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mro/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: HiRISE
the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter&amp;rsquo;sHiRISE camera shows weathered craters and windblown deposits in southern.A striking shade of blue in standard HiRISE image colors,to the human eye the area would probably look grey or a little reddish.But human eyes have not gazedacross this terrain, unless you count the eyes of NASA astronautsin the scifi novel by Andy Weir.The novel chronicles the adventures of Mark Watney,an astronaut stranded at the fictional Mars mission Ares 3 landing sitecorresponding to the coordinates of this cropped HiRISE frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ria de Vigo, Vigo, España (© JulioConde/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/reconquistavigo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/reconquistavigo/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © JulioConde/Getty Images
¿Estás preparado para un viaje en el tiempo? Los vigueses se visten de historia cada primavera, cuando sus calles retroceden a 1809 para celebrar la Reconquista de Vigo. Este evento celebra un hito en la historia que marcó un antes y un después en la ciudad olívica, convirtiendo a Vigo en la primera ciudad europea que logró expulsar a las tropas napoleónicas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>オカバンゴ・デルタ, ボツワナ (© Ibrahim Suha Derbent/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/antelopebotswana/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:00:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/antelopebotswana/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ibrahim Suha Derbent/Getty Images
アフリカ南部のボツワナにあるオカバンゴ・デルタは、自然美と生態系の重要性から世界遺産に登録されており、多種多様な生物が生息しています。特徴的な赤褐色の毛皮と竪琴のような形をした角で知られるリーチュエも、ここで自由に走っています…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poço encantado em Chapada Diamantina, Bahia (© Cavan Images/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chapadadiamantinabahia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chapadadiamantinabahia/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>樱花树枝上的灰胸绣眼鸟，韩国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/whiteeyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 02:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/whiteeyes/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © TigerSeo/Getty Images
跟这些在韩国赏樱花的灰胸绣眼鸟打个招呼吧！它们身披黄羽，身形滚圆，个子小巧，喜欢成群出没。虽然这种雀形目鸟类原产于非洲、澳大拉西亚和亚洲，但由于引进的关系，在法属波利尼西亚和夏威夷等地也能看到它们的身影。灰胸绣眼鸟又名银绣眼鸟，有各种颜色和图案，但它们都有标志性的眼圈。它们嗜甜如命，爱吃花蜜，但也不挑食，水果、昆虫和浆果它们也喜欢吃。在阳春三月，让我们赞美这些为春天增添一抹奇妙色彩的小精灵吧！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerezos en flor en el Valle del Jerte, Cáceres, España (© Mario Elias Munoz Valencia/iStock/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/floweingberrys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 06:00:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/floweingberrys/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Mario Elias Munoz Valencia/iStock/Getty Images
Cada año, el Valle del Jerte se tiñe de blanco nupcial para dar la bienvenida a la primavera con su espectacular Fiesta del Cerezo en Flor. Este año el esperado evento de la naturaleza se celebra desde el 16 de marzo al 3 de mayo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>巴西亚马逊上空巨大的砧状云</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/amazonclouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 02:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/amazonclouds/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © NASA
“当云层像岩石和高塔一样出现时，地球就会因频繁的阵雨而焕然一新”，这句古老的气象谚语对于雷暴云（又名积雨云或砧状云）来说有几分道理。而照片中展示的正是砧状云。今天，在世界气象日，我们向大气层的这个奇迹致敬。为了纪念世界气象组织于1950年3月23日成立，世界气象日的首次纪念活动于1961年的3月23日举行。但这一天不仅仅是对历史的致敬，还是为了呼吁人们认识到气象学在我们生活中的重要作用。天气预报可能并不总是可靠的，但由于卫星和超级计算机等技术的进步，天气预报已经取得了长足的进步。由于这些进步，全球天气模型可以提供长达16天的预报，龙卷风预警的平均提前时间从1974年的-15分钟缩短到今天的15分钟左右。让我们为气象学已取得的进展和将要取得的进步欢呼吧!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>蓝泉，蒂怀霍步道，新西兰</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/waikatowater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 02:00:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/waikatowater/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ian Beattie/Alamy Stock Photo
今天是世界水日，这是一个已有31年历史的传统节日，在全球范围内具有重要的影响力。世界水日的宗旨是唤起公众的节水意识，加强水资源保护。水是既可以解渴，又能灌溉庄稼。如果没有水，就会破坏社会的繁荣和稳定。世界经济论坛将水危机列为全球最大的风险之一，全球仍有22亿人无法获得干净的饮用水，联合国的这次纪念活动正是为了呼吁大家采取行动解决这一危机。从教育论坛里的科普宣传到各地组织的清理活动，每一个行动，或大或小，都是有用的。今年世界水日的主题是“以水促和平”，当我们在水问题上开展合作时，就会产生积极的连锁效应。所以，你准备好加入这股浪潮了吗？</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Jefferson Memorial during the Cherry Blossom Festival, Washington, DC (© f11photo/Shutterstock)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cherryblossomsdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 06:01:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cherryblossomsdc/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © f11photo/Shutterstock
Want to experience spring in all its glory? If you head to the National Cherry Blossom Festival in Washington, DC, you&amp;rsquo;re in for a blooming good time! The festival commemorates the 3,000 cherry trees given to the city by the mayor of Tokyo in 1912. Twelve varieties were originally gifted but these days most of the trees are either Yoshino or Kwanzan cherries. Those circling the Tidal Basin, the location of the Jefferson Memorial featured in today&amp;rsquo;s image, are Yoshino trees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Château d&#39;If, Calanques, Marseille, Bouches du Rhône (© MOIRENC Camille/Hemis/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chateauif/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/chateauif/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © MOIRENC Camille/Hemis/Alamy Stock Photo
Le 20 mars, l&amp;rsquo;ONU célèbre la Journée de la langue française, l&amp;rsquo;une des six « Journées des langues » consacrées aux langues officielles de l&amp;rsquo;organisation. Instaurées en 2010 pour promouvoir le multilinguisme et la diversité culturelle, elles ont pour objectif de sensibiliser à l&amp;rsquo;histoire, la culture et l&amp;rsquo;importance de chaque langue. La date de la Journée de la langue française commémore la création de l&amp;rsquo;Agence de coopération culturelle et technique en 1970, devenue l’Organisation internationale de la Francophonie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布恩迪国家公园，乌干达</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bwindinationalforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bwindinationalforest/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Art Wolfe/DanitaDelimont.com
今天是国际森林日，让我们走出家门，扎根林地吧！森林是地球上重要的生态系统之一，为了提高人们对保护森林和欣赏森林景观的意识，就在11年前的今天，联合国设立了国际森林日。据悉，世界各地的林地占地球陆地面积的30%以上，林地中的树木种类繁多，令人难以置信，据估计，全球共有超6万种不同种类的树。森林在提供食物、水和药物等基础资源方面发挥着至关重要的作用。今天的图片展示的是乌干达的布恩迪国家公园，这里有160种树木和100种蕨类植物，以及世界上50%的山地大猩猩种群。森林中的树木之间还生长着茂密的竹林，导致人们在这片森林中寸步难行，因此布恩迪国家公园又名“难以穿越的森林”。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Picturesque Equinox Sunset</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 09:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/twan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Alan Dyer
What&amp;rsquo;s that at the end of the road?The Sun.Many towns have roads that run east-west, and on two days each year, the Sun rises and sets .Today, in some parts of the world (tomorrow in others), is one of those days: an . Not only is this a day of equal night and day time, but also a day when the precisely to the east and sets due west.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zorro rojo con su cachorro en Washington (© Chase Dekker/Minden Pictures)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/redfox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 06:02:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/redfox/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Chase Dekker/Minden Pictures
En el frescor del bosque, un zorro rojo guía con orgullo a su cachorro, celebrando a su manera el Día del Padre. Este día, en España, se vive con la misma ternura que este padre zorro cuida de su joven cría. Coincidiendo con el día de San José, el 19 de marzo es un día sagrado para el corazón familiar, un momento para honrar la dedicación y el amor de quienes nos guían por la vida.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cave Dale and Peveril Castle in Castleton, Peak District National Park, Derbyshire, England (© James Osmond/Alamy)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springcavedale/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 06:02:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springcavedale/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © James Osmond/Alamy
Peveril Castle was once a medieval fortress, standing tall on a limestone outcrop. Its ruins now overlook the village of Castleton in the Peak District in Derbyshire, England. Construction of the castle began shortly after the Norman conquest in the 11th century, although it wasn&amp;rsquo;t completed until the 14th century. From the castle, visitors can enjoy views of Cave Dale, a ravine that was carved by glacial meltwater over many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>鸟瞰春日盛开的樱花，中国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springequinox2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 02:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springequinox2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © outcast85/Getty images
春分时节，中国大部分地区已进入明媚的春天。此时，严寒已过，气温迅速回升。春分过后，人们开始陆续外出。在户外活动中，放风筝是一项重要的项目。古代还有春分戴花、饮酒的习俗。在这一天，无论男女老少都会在头发上戴花。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tree frog on leaf (© Tetsuya Tanooka/DEEPOL by plainpicture)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springfrog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 06:00:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/springfrog/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Tetsuya Tanooka/DEEPOL by plainpicture
In some parts of the world, the arrival of spring is announced by the guttural chorus of tree frogs. As their name suggests, these frogs spend most of their lives in trees. Belonging to species within the Neobatrachia suborder, it is characterised by its arboreal lifestyle, spending a significant portion of its life in trees. Despite their diverse origins within Neobatrachia, these tree-dwelling frogs share the common adaptation of inhabiting arboreal environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vista aerea dell&#39;Altare della Patria, Roma, Italia (© Nico De Pasquale Photography/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/altaredellapatria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/altaredellapatria/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大象岩，古城欧拉，沙特阿拉伯</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/elephantrock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 02:00:39 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/elephantrock/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Lubo Ivanko/Shutterstock
经过数百万年的时间，大自然雕琢出了这片耀眼夺目的砂岩地貌，名为大象岩。该岩石高达117英尺，位于沙特阿拉伯古城欧拉附近，由于风水的侵蚀，它呈现出大象的形状，并成为了该地区的著名地标。日落时，夕阳洒在这片沙漠上，为红色的“猛犸象”及其周围金色的沙子镀上一层温暖的光辉。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dhanushkodi, Rameshwaram harbour, Pamban bridge and near by areas (© gulfu photography/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/pambanbridge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 06:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/pambanbridge/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © gulfu photography/Getty Images
Get ready to explore the offbeat charm of Rameswaram Island! Occupying a significant position between peninsular India and Sri Lanka, this island, also known as Pamban Island, is within the Adam&amp;rsquo;s Bridge (Ram Setu) archipelago. As the second-largest island in the region, it is anchored by the pilgrimage hub of Rameswaram, a bustling town steeped in spiritual significance. Here, spanning across the waters of the Indian Ocean, Pamban Bridge is a vital railway link, connecting the town of Mandapam on mainland India with Rameswaram on the Island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>圣菲尼安湾，凯里郡，爱尔兰</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/stfiniansbay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 02:00:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/stfiniansbay/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Atlantide Phototravel/Getty Images
今天，全球数百万具有爱尔兰血统的人都在庆祝圣帕特里克节。圣帕特里克是爱尔兰国家的守护神，大约在公元432年，他将基督教引入到爱尔兰。公元461年3月17日，圣帕特里克逝世，这一天成为了爱尔兰纪念他的日子。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lindenallee, baumgesäumter Fußweg durch den Park im Frühling (© AVTG/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/avenuelimetrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:02:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/avenuelimetrees/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © AVTG/Getty Images
Mit den ersten zarten Sonnenstrahlen des Frühlings erwacht die Lindenallee zu neuem Leben. Ihre knospenden Zweige wiegen sich sanft im leichten Frühlingswind, während das zarte Grün langsam die grauen Zweige umhüllt. Ein Teppich aus duftenden Blütenblättern legt sich über den Weg und das leise Rascheln unter den Füßen kündigt den Frühling an. Vögel zwitschern fröhlich in den Zweigen und verkünden mit ihrem Gesang die Ankunft der wärmeren Tage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fiesta de las Fallas de Valencia, Comunidad Valenciana, España (© Gonzalo Azumendi/Getty images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/falleraswomenvalencia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:01:57 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/falleraswomenvalencia/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Gonzalo Azumendi/Getty images
¡Llegan las Fallas de Valencia, un espectáculo de luz, arte y tradición! Desde su humilde comienzo con carpinteros quemando restos de madera en honor a San José, esta festividad ha sido reconocida por la UNESCO e inscrita en su Lista Representativa del Patrimonio Cultural Inmaterial de la Humanidad. Imagina gigantescas esculturas, las &amp;ldquo;fallas&amp;rdquo;, emergiendo como guardianas de las calles, cada una ansiosa por contar su historia antes de sucumbir al fuego en la &amp;ldquo;cremà&amp;rdquo;, así como su asombroso espectáculo pirotécnico.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champs de tulipes dans la vallée du Fraser, Abbotsford, Colombie-Britannique, Canada (© LeonU/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tulipabbotsford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 06:01:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tulipabbotsford/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © LeonU/Getty Images
Le décompte avant l&amp;rsquo;arrivée officielle du printemps a commencé! Les tulipes de la vallée du Fraser, mises en lumière dans l&amp;rsquo;image d&amp;rsquo;aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, s&amp;rsquo;épanouissent dans une explosion de teintes vibrantes en préparation du festival des tulipes d&amp;rsquo;Abbotsford, prévu pour le mois d&amp;rsquo;avril. Cette terre fertile est généreusement arrosée par les eaux du fleuve Fraser, qui serpente à travers la frontière nord de la ville.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>正在吃竹子的大熊猫，中国成都</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bamboopanda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bamboopanda/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Suzi Eszterhas/Minden Pictures
你喜欢观看熊猫“滚滚”那令人轻松视频吗？这些啃食竹子的动物有着独特的黑白外衣和俏皮的举止，多年来一直吸引着人们的目光。以至于在1961年，世界自然基金会将这种动物作为其标志性标识。但你知道有一天是用来庆祝它们的吗？3月16日是国家熊猫日，旨在提高人们保护大熊猫和生态环境的意识。大熊猫的自然栖息地遭到破坏，这意味着它们变得十分脆弱；为了遏制这种威胁，中国建立了大约50个保护区。幸运的是，2016年，大熊猫从濒危物种重新归类为易危物种了。不过，现如今野外大熊猫数量不足2000只，保护大熊猫的战斗远未结束。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alameda de Palmeiras Imperiales in the Botanical Garden of Rio de Janeiro (© Marcia Silva de Mendonca/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cancaodoexilio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 06:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/cancaodoexilio/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>安沙波利哥沙漠州立公园，美国加利福尼亚州</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/anzaborregobloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/anzaborregobloom/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Stephen Matera/Tandem Stills + Motion
也许距离春天伊始还有好些天，但是加州最大的州立公园——安沙波利哥沙漠州立公园的野花已经在这里向你问好了！每年春天，这片贫瘠的沙漠都会经历一次戏剧性的改变。向日葵、沙漠菊和蒲公英等花朵竞相绽放，形成色彩斑斓的奇观。对于那些想要寻求更多冒险体验的游客来说，从半岛山脉仙人掌丛生的丘陵到峡谷、荒地和天然棕榈绿洲，这个公园有很多可供选择的地方。此外，作为指定的国际黑暗天空公园，这里还是绝佳的观星地点。除了自然奇观之外，占地超过60万英亩的公园还拥有丰富的文化和历史遗产，如古老的象形文字或岩画。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wat Phra Ngam，大城府历史公园，泰国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ayutthayatree/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 02:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ayutthayatree/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © boonchai wedmakawand/Alamy Stock Photo
有人这样说过，世界上唯一不变的是变化。然而，在数学里却有许多固定不变的常数，今天，我们要庆祝的也许是其中最著名的一个：π。圆周率是圆的周长与直径之比，约为3.14159。每年的3月14日，全世界的数学爱好者都会用烘焙来庆祝圆周率π日——这既是对数学常数π的庆祝，也是对其同音字，美味的“派”的庆祝。它始于1988年，当时物理学家拉里·肖将日期（3/14）与这个常数的前三位数联系起来。今天，数学家和爱好者们用吃派和背诵π来庆祝圆周率日。你知道吗，当你的时钟敲响1:59时，表示你离圆周率的实际值又近了三位小数。圆周率无处不在，甚至在大自然中也是如此。图中是泰国大城府寺庙的一棵菩提树，其形状就像圆周率的符号。无论你是数学怪才，还是只是为了享受美食，每个人都可以享受“派”节！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>小红鹳飞越马加迪湖,肯尼亚</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/magadiflamingos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 02:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/magadiflamingos/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Vicki Jauron, Babylon and Beyond Photography/Getty Images
多么不可思议的景色啊！这张航拍照片展示了以肯尼亚马加迪湖为背景的小红鹳群。小红鹳是六种火烈鸟之一，以其鲜艳的粉红色羽毛和独特的觅食行为而闻名。由于喙的构造，这些鸟喜欢在水面附近进食。它们主要栖息在碳酸盐浓度较高的非洲苏打湖。马加迪湖就是这样一个充满蓝藻和海藻的苏打湖，为火烈鸟提供了充足的营养。成千上万只火烈鸟聚集在湖边的壮观景象揭示了这些独特生态系统的重要性。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Full Plankton Moon</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/institute_of_physics_in_opava/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Petr Horálek
What glows in the night?This night a combination of usual and unusual glows.Perhaps the most usual glow was from, a potentially familiar object.The full Moon&amp;rsquo;s nearly results from the observer being near.As the Moon sets, ands in preferentially scatter out blue light, makingthe appear reddish whennear the horizon. Perhaps the mostwas from the bioluminescent, likely less familiar objects.These glow blue, it is thought, primarily toand.In this case, the glow was caused primarily byplankton-containing waves crashing onto the beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>東大寺, 奈良県 奈良市 (© Buddhika Weerasinghe/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/omizutorinew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/omizutorinew/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Buddhika Weerasinghe/Getty Images
3 月 1 日から 14 日まで、東大寺二月堂では、修二会という伝統的な法会が行われています。行中の 3 月 12 日の深夜には、僧侶たちが二月堂前の若狭井という井戸から「お香水」を汲み上る「お水取り」の儀式が行われます。十一面観音にその水をお供えして天下安穏などを祈願します…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布莱斯峡谷国家公园，犹他州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/brycesnow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 02:00:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/brycesnow/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Jim Patterson/Tandem Stills + Motion
徒步是游览犹他州布莱斯峡谷国家公园这些迷人的红色石柱的最佳选择！公园里的徒步小径可以引导您穿行于世界上最大的石柱岩群之间，这些石柱是由侵蚀作用形成的岩石尖顶。这些马蹄形的天然露天剧场会随着阳光的照射而变化，营造出了一种超现实的景观。该地区最初居住着美洲原住民部落，包括派尤特人。虽然没有证据表明他们曾在此长期居住，但派尤特族印第安人曾利用庞沙冈特高原进行季节性狩猎和采集。布莱斯峡谷于1928年被指定为国家公园，峡谷内分布着多个观景点，如灵感点、约文帕点和彩虹点，可将周围的景致尽收眼底。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Total Eclipse at the End of the World</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 09:00:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/moonglow.net/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Fred Bruenjes
Would you go to the end of the world to see a total eclipse of the Sun?If you did, would you be surprised to find someone else In 2003, the , the Moon, Antarctica, and two photographers all lined up in during an unusual. Even given the extreme location, a group of ventured near thebottom of the world to momentarydisappearance of the . One of the treasures collected was the &amp;ndash; a composite of four separate imagesdigitally combined to realistically simulate how the adaptive human the eclipse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A koala sleeping in a eucalyptus tree, Australia (© Anton Rogozin/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sleepykoala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:01:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sleepykoala/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Anton Rogozin/Getty Images
This sleepy koala may inspire you to catch some Z&amp;rsquo;s. These adorable Australian marsupials can sleep up to 20 hours a day, which helps them conserve the little energy they get from their eucalyptus-based diet. Koalas move slowly when awake, spend most of their time tucked into nooks in trees, and have a lower body temperature than other animals of their size. The koala is an arboreal herbivorous marsupial, it is uniquely adapted to its native habitat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rathaus Ulm, Astronomische Uhr aus dem 16. Jahrhundert, Ulm, Baden-Württemberg (© Hemis/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/astrologicalclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:01:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/astrologicalclock/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Hemis/Alamy Stock Photo
Werfen Sie einen Blick auf dieses Meisterwerk. Ist es nicht unglaublich, dass diese Uhr um 1520 gebaut wurde? Wir befanden uns noch im Mittelalter und der Glaube, dass sich alles im Universum um die Erde dreht, dass sogenannte geozentrische Weltbild, war fest verankert. Diese Uhr am Ulmer Rathaus zeigt nicht nur die Zeit an, sondern auch astronomische Daten wie den Stand der Sonne, des Mondes und der Sterne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Mer de Glace, Chamonix, massif du Mont-Blanc, Haute-Savoie, France (© Hagenmuller Jean-François/Hemis.fr)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/montblancglacier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:01:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/montblancglacier/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Hagenmuller Jean-François/Hemis.fr
La Mer de Glace, l’un des glaciers les plus célèbres des Alpes françaises, est située sur le versant septentrional du massif du Mont-Blanc, près de Chamonix. Elle s&amp;rsquo;étend sur environ 7 kilomètres de long et 200 mètres de profondeur, c&amp;rsquo;est le plus grand glacier de France. Sa formation remonte à des millénaires, façonnée par le mouvement lent et constant de la glace.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>追悼イベントの灯籠, 宮城県 名取市 (© Satoshi Takahashi/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/earthquake2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:00:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/earthquake2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Satoshi Takahashi/Getty Images
今日 3 月 11 日は東日本大震災から 13 年目となります。被災地をはじめ、全国的に追悼式が行われます。本日、宮城県名取市の震災メモリアル公園では、全国から寄せられた絵を絵灯籠にして展示し、犠牲者への追悼と復興を願います…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mute swan mother and cygnet, Stanpit Marsh, England (© LecartPhotos/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/motheringsundaymuteswan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 06:00:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/motheringsundaymuteswan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © LecartPhotos/Alamy Stock Photo
As spring breathes new life into the world, a time-honoured tradition—Mothering Sunday—is a time to celebrate the nurturing spirit of mothers. It might be often called Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day in the United Kingdom, but it has no connection with the American Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day. This holiday&amp;rsquo;s roots stretch back to the 16th century when it was a day for folks to return to their &amp;lsquo;mother church&amp;rsquo; for a special service on the fourth Sunday of Lent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prosecco山丘，科内利亚诺和瓦尔多比亚德内，威内托大区，意大利</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/proseccoitaly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 03:17:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/proseccoitaly/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Richard T. Nowitz/Getty Images
科内利亚诺和瓦尔多比亚德内的Prosecco丘陵是大自然与人类智慧完美结合的地方。由于其独特性，这些山丘已被联合国教科文组织列入世界遗产名录。特殊的丘陵地带给该地带来了由葡萄园和树林构成的有机环境。而在马赛克般的景观中脱颖而出的小村庄和葡萄园，却只是让这个地方显得独一无二的部分因素。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elephants crossing river in Jim Corbett National Park, India (© ABHILASH VISWA PICASSO/Shutterstock)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/morningelephants/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 06:00:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/morningelephants/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © ABHILASH VISWA PICASSO/Shutterstock
Hold onto your hats and binoculars, because in Jim Corbett National Park, the river is no ordinary waterway—it&amp;rsquo;s an elephant expressway! India&amp;rsquo;s oldest national park was established in 1936 and named after the naturalist and conservationist Jim Corbett. Housed in the foothills of the Himalayas near the popular hill-station of Nainital, the Jim Corbett National Park is known for its significant tiger population. During the summer months, the park becomes a bustling hub of wildlife activity, with Indian elephants frequently spotted roaming in herds numbering several hundred.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garça-branca-grande (Ardea alba) em pé em uma lagoa de vitórias-régias, Pantanal (© Geraldi Corsi/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ardealba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ardealba/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>圣哈辛托大厦的机械钟，博蒙特，美国德克萨斯州</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/beaumontclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 02:00:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/beaumontclock/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Richard T. Nowitz/Getty Images
今天的时间至关重要：三月的第二个星期日标志着夏令时的开始。今天凌晨2点开始，时钟向前拨动一小时，这意味着今天白天会“多”出一个小时。本杰明·富兰克林通常被认为是夏令时的发明者，但第一个真正意义上提出拨动时钟建议的人是新西兰昆虫学家乔治·赫德森。在1895年，因为他想在白天有更多的时间来采集昆虫，他提出了这一改动。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Tarantula Zone</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 09:00:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/roberto_colombari/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：nasa. copyright: Robert Gendler
,also known as 30 Doradus, is more than a thousand light-years in diameter,a giant star forming region within nearby satellite galaxy the.About 180 thousand light-years away, it&amp;rsquo;s the largest,most violent star forming region known in the whole LocalGroup of galaxies.The cosmic arachnid sprawls across,an assembly of image data from large space- and ground-based telescopes. (NGC 2070),intense radiation, stellar winds, and supernova shocksfrom the central young cluster of massive stars cataloged as R136energize the nebular glow and shape the spidery filaments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>比斯第恶土，新墨西哥州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bistiblue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 02:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bistiblue/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Ian Shive/Tandem Stills + Motion
时间是伟大的变革者，它改变着世界，也改变着我们所有人。例如，新墨西哥州的这片名为比斯第恶土的荒地，曾经是一片郁郁葱葱的热带森林。近7000万年前，这里没有扭曲的地形和高耸的尖塔，而是一群白垩纪晚期恐龙的家园，包括甲龙、鸭嘴龙和强大的霸王龙。如今，这里到处都是另一种奇观，岩层看起来更像是雕塑，而不是自然现象。比斯第恶土的名字“Bisti/De-Na-Zin”是以纳瓦霍语命名的：“Bisti” 的意思是 &amp;ldquo;在土坯岩层中&amp;rdquo;，“De-Na-Zin” 则来自附近的 &amp;ldquo;站立的仙起重机&amp;quot;石刻。来到四角地区的游客一定不要错过这片由页岩和砂岩组成的超凡脱俗的景观。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>テート・モダン, イギリス ロンドン (© Stephen Chung/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tatelightup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 06:00:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tatelightup/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Stephen Chung/Alamy Stock Photo
今日 3 月 8 日は国際女性デーです。この日は、1909 年に米国で始まった女性の日が、1917 年にストライキを行ったロシアの女性たちの活動をきっかけに、 3 月 8 日に定着しました。そして、1977 年には国連により公式に認められました…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>伊瓜苏大瀑布鸟瞰图，巴西</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/iguazufalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 02:00:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/iguazufalls/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Nido Huebl/Shutterstock
伊瓜苏大瀑布以其宏伟且独特的美景吸引着游客，是南美洲最令人印象深刻的自然宝藏之一。这个壮观的瀑布位于巴西和阿根廷的交界处，不仅是一个不可错过的旅游景点，也是全球公认的瑰宝。1986年，伊瓜苏大瀑布被联合国教科文组织评为世界遗产，并被世界新七大奇迹基金会评选为世界七大自然奇观之一。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roques de Benet，埃尔斯港自然公园，加泰罗尼亚，西班牙</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tarragonaspain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 02:00:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tarragonaspain/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Sergi Boixader/Alamy Stock Photo
奇特的山峰耸立在埃尔斯港自然公园的上空，这是一组位于西班牙加泰罗尼亚地区波特斯德托尔托萨贝塞特山的岩石群。这组岩石群里最高的山峰海拔约3,330英尺，从山顶上俯瞰埃布罗三角洲，可以看到溪流和松树林，还有通往山中的小径。该山的名字中包含“Benet”一词，这个词源于阿拉伯语，暗示着该地区有着丰富多彩的过去。如今，埃尔斯港自然公园是各种动物的家园，从野生山羊和水獭到秃鹫和老鹰，园区内物种丰富。不过，动物并不是该地区唯一的“居民”。山脚下还坐落着一个具有社区意识的村庄，村民们仍然保持着共同的传统，例如使用植物纤维来制作篮子和厨房用具的古老工艺。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nanday, família dos periquitos, Pantanal (© Pedro Hélder da Costa Pinheiro/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nandayparakeet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:00:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/nandayparakeet/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wahclella Falls，哥伦比亚河峡谷，俄勒冈州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/wahclellafalls/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 02:00:21 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/wahclellafalls/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Eric Vogt/Tandem Stills + Motion
在俄勒冈州一处狭缝型峡谷的尽头，有一个特别的地方正等待着徒步旅行者去探索：瓦克莱拉瀑布。其水源来自哥伦比亚河的支流坦纳河，这个瀑布的名字是由马扎马登山俱乐部的成员以美国原住民村庄的名字命名的。走到步行道的尽头，游客可以观赏到壮观的两级瀑布，水流从350英尺高的地方坠落到下面的水潭中，而这个水潭正是一个绝佳的玩水、纳凉胜地，当你在里面游泳的时候，可别忘了留意附近的水鸫（也被称为美洲河乌），这是一种以瀑布为家的鸟类。人们可以看到它们沿着溪流飞翔，偶尔也会潜入水中。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>曼谷的交通圈和高速公路，泰国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bangkokcircle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 02:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bangkokcircle/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Avigator Fortuner/Shutterstock
在生机勃勃的泰国，曼谷这座城市充满了活力！这是一座占地面积超600平方英里的城市，其常住人口预估超过1000万人，占泰国总人口的15%以上。作为泰国的首都，曼谷拥有繁华的城市基础设施，而复杂的交通圈和高速公路网正是其特色。1864年竣工的石龙军路，是曼谷第一条利用现代方法铺设的马路。石龙军路的建成亦是曼谷历史上的重要节点，曼谷的主要交通方式自此从水上交通向陆路交通转变。而1972年引入的复杂的高架快速路网和廊曼收费公路的建成则使得开车进出城更加方便。多年来，曼谷的交通网络在不断地发展，以满足城市扩张的需求。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>从蒙特维多看到的阿雷纳尔火山,哥斯达黎加</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/arenalcostarica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/arenalcostarica/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Lukas Bischoff/Getty Images
热带国家哥斯达黎加在向你招手！图中展示的圆锥形的阿雷纳尔火山高达5437英尺，屹立于周围的热带雨林以及该国最大的湖泊阿雷纳尔湖之上。1968年，在一次大规模的喷发中，这座沉睡的火山咆哮着苏醒了，当时的岩石飞溅了半英里多。而最近一次的大规模火山活动发生在2010年，如今，这座曾被熔岩照亮过山峰正处于休眠状态。对于观鸟者而言，阿雷纳尔火山国家公园是一个必游之地，公园内拥有500多种鸟类，除此之外，该公园还是各种动植物的家园，包括赤短角鹿、美洲狮、白脸卷尾猴、兰花、蝎尾蕉和蕨类植物。高高的阿雷纳尔火山俯瞰着这些热带树木，形成了一副壮观而美丽的风景。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>下鴨神社の流し雛, 京都 (© masahiro Makino/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hinamatsuri2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 06:00:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/hinamatsuri2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © masahiro Makino/Getty Images
今日 3 月 3 日はひな祭り。桃の花やひな人形を飾り、女の子の成長を祝う日です。ひな祭りの歴史は古く、平安時代の上巳の節句に行われた、紙で作ったひな人形を川で流す「流し雛」の行事が起源とされています…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electric guitars and amplifiers (© Third Eye Images/The Image Bank/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/britawardsguitarsuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 06:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/britawardsguitarsuk/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Third Eye Images/The Image Bank/Getty Images
If music be the food of love, tonight we&amp;rsquo;re in for quite a feast. It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again: the Brit Awards are here! Starting in 1977 as part of Queen Elizabeth II&amp;rsquo;s silver jubilee celebrations, the Brit Awards have grown to become the biggest night in the British music industry&amp;rsquo;s calendar. There are 15 awards up for grabs, and nominees include Blur and Little Simz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s suffrage parade on Fifth Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, October 23, 1915 (© Bettmann/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/suffrageparade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 06:06:44 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/suffrageparade/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Bettmann/Getty Images
Every March, we celebrate Women&amp;rsquo;s History Month, a tribute to the generations of women who have shaped our past and are inspiring our present. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to highlight a crucial step that was taken for a more representative democracy—the women&amp;rsquo;s suffrage movement. This image shows a sea of determined faces in a 1915 Manhattan suffrage parade. Pioneers like Susan B. Anthony and Lucy Stone spearheaded this effort, which culminated in the historic 19th Amendment in 1920, which granted women the right to vote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blaireau européen (© Milan Zygmunt/Shutterstock)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/badger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 06:06:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/badger/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Milan Zygmunt/Shutterstock
Le blaireau européen est un mammifère omnivore appartenant à la famille des mustélidés. Reconnaissable par sa silhouette trapue, son museau pointu, ses oreilles arrondies et son pelage dense de couleur gris-argent, on le trouve dans tout le territoire français, des régions boisées aux zones rurales, en passant par les collines et les prairies. Malheureusement, il souffre d’un désamour injustifié. Les agriculteurs et les jardiniers le considèrent souvent comme une nuisance, mais il joue un rôle essentiel dans l’écosystème.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>クルーガー国立公園のヒョウ, 南アフリカ (© Tonino De Marco/Minden Pictures)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/krugerleopard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 06:03:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/krugerleopard/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Tonino De Marco/Minden Pictures
明日 3 月 3 日は世界野生生物の日であり、野生動植物の国際的な取引を規制するための条約である「ワシントン条約」が 1973 年 3 月 3 日に採択されたことを記念した日です…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coucher de soleil sur la rivière glacée Wheaton, Yukon, Canada (© Robert Postma/All Canada Photos/Alamy Stock Photo)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/wheatonriveryukon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 06:02:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/wheatonriveryukon/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Robert Postma/All Canada Photos/Alamy Stock Photo
Dans le nord du Canada se trouve le Yukon, une terre riche en histoire et en paysages accidentés. Son nom, « Yu-kun-ah », vient du mot gwich&amp;rsquo;in signifiant « grand fleuve ». La ruée vers l&amp;rsquo;or du Klondike en 1896 a rendu la région célèbre, attirant de nombreux chercheurs de fortune dans ses vastes étendues sauvages. Malgré sa faible population, le Yukon offre aux visiteurs la possibilité d&amp;rsquo;explorer les villes historiques de la ruée vers l&amp;rsquo;or, de découvrir l&amp;rsquo;art indigène dans ses musées et d&amp;rsquo;assister à divers événements annuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filhotes de coruja-buraqueira recém-nascidos, Pantanal (© Bence Mate/Minden)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/owlchicks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 06:01:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/owlchicks/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright:
have no desc</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The holy city of Varanasi, India (© Jesse Rockwell/Shutterstock)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/holyvaranasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 06:00:54 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/holyvaranasi/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Jesse Rockwell/Shutterstock
Known for its sacred ghats and bustling alleys, Varanasi is a city on the banks of the Ganges in the northern part of India. Located about 120 kilometres downstream from Prayagraj, at the confluence of the Ganges and Yamuna rivers, it is a major pilgrimage site for Hindu spirituality and tradition. The mighty Ganges is said to have originated in Lord Shiva&amp;rsquo;s hair and grown into the revered river that flows through Varanasi today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>モディカ, イタリア (© Sandro Bisaro/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/modicaitaly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 06:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/modicaitaly/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Sandro Bisaro/Getty Images
ここはイタリアのシチリア島にある世界遺産の街、モディカです。1693 年に起きた大地震により建物がほぼ全壊しましたが、再建時に後期バロック様式が採用され、見事に復興を遂げました…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>德国草地上的蝴蝶</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/schmetterlingswiese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 02:00:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/schmetterlingswiese/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Albert Fertl/Getty Images
春天就在眼前，第一缕春的气息充盈着我们的肺腑，让我们长舒一口气吧！在鲜花盛开的草地上，蝴蝶在温暖的阳光下翩翩起舞，这正是春天即将到来的完美写照。每只蝴蝶都是大自然的得意作品，都有着独特的花纹及鲜艳的色彩。蝴蝶轻舞，草地上充满了生命的脉动，空气中弥漫着淡淡的优雅气息。这是一个真正的奇观，它能调动我们的感官，让我们的灵魂飞扬起来。看看这些奇妙的生灵，它们展示出来的轻盈和蜕变，正是我们应该学习和思考的两个方面。停下脚步，用目光临摹蝴蝶优雅的旋转，它们在提醒我们欣赏生活中的小奇迹，用新的眼光看待这个世界。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plaza de España, Sevilla, España (© KavalenkavaVolha/Getty images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sevilleandalusiaday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 06:01:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sevilleandalusiaday/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © KavalenkavaVolha/Getty images
Admiremos la belleza de la Plaza de España en Sevilla, corazón de Andalucía, declarada bien de interés cultural, con su majestuosidad semicircular, sus torres que rozan el cielo y rodeada por un canal cruzado por puentes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>バーミリオン・クリフ国定公園, 米国 アリゾナ州 (© Yva Momatiuk and John Eastcott/Minden Pictures)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/vermilioncliffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 06:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/vermilioncliffs/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Yva Momatiuk and John Eastcott/Minden Pictures
バーミリオン・クリフ国定公園は、2000 年に設立された米国のアリゾナ州にある自然公園です。風や水によって削られた奇妙な形の岩や、朱色の断崖絶壁が圧倒的な景観を作り出しています…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>欧亚红松鼠</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/leapingsquirrel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 01:24:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/leapingsquirrel/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Westend61/Getty Images
你是一个“跳跃者”吗？不，不是像这只欧亚红松鼠那样跳跃，而是指在闰日出生的人！闰年是日历上的一种奇怪现象，因为地球的轨道和我们通常计算的年份稍有不同，地球绕太阳公转一周需要365天5小时48分46秒，为了解决这个余数，二月每四年就会多出一天，也就是闰日。这一概念可追溯到古罗马，并在教皇格列高利十三世于1582年引入的公历中得到完善。虽然这一天的目的是让我们的一年与阳历保持一致，但它也可以作为额外的一天为即将来临的春天做准备！世界各地都有独特的习俗来纪念闰日和闰年。在爱尔兰和英国，女人向男人求婚；在希腊，闰年结婚被认为会带来不幸；在法国，每四年才出一期的讽刺报刊会在闰日出版。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>班堡城堡，诺森伯兰郡，英格兰</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bamburghcastleuk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:52:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bamburghcastleuk/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Blackbeck/Getty Images
班堡城堡坐落在英格兰诺森伯兰郡班堡地区，矗立在海岸旁边突出的黑色火山岩上。图中所展示的是班堡沙丘，班堡城堡和附近的海滩就掩映在该地区独特的沙质地貌中。班堡城堡曾经是盎格鲁-撒克逊人的战略要塞，经过几个世纪的演变，形成了如今这座宏伟的建筑。这座城堡在抵御维京人的入侵中曾发挥了关键作用。然而，北欧人摧毁了城堡最初的防御工事，之后在中世纪期间又对其进行了重大改造。城堡还是古代诺森伯兰王国的所在地，这是一个中世纪的盎格鲁-撒克逊王国，位于今天的英格兰北部和苏格兰东南部。班堡城堡面朝北海，被生机盎然的绿草所环绕，怀抱如此美景，班堡城堡成为了许多电影的取景地，比如《麦克白》、《夺宝奇兵：命运之盘》、《艾芬豪》等。
BamburghCastleUK </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大峡谷国家公园，亚利桑那州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/grandcanyonwinter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:52:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/grandcanyonwinter/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Jeremy Janus/Getty Images
祝大峡谷国家公园生日快乐！今天是由亚利桑那州科罗拉多河雕刻而成的著名峡谷的一个里程碑：自伍德罗·威尔逊总统于1919年将其指定为国家公园以来，已经过去了105年。大峡谷是由河流、风和山体滑坡形成的独特景观，它的起源可以追溯到500万到600万年前。大峡谷承载着印第安人、欧美拓荒者和旅行者的故事，还有陡峭的山谷和五颜六色的岩层等地质奇观。所有的这些区域都由国家公园管理局监管。除了在科罗拉多河上巡游、参加时光之路徒步旅行或登上沙漠景观瞭望塔等旅游冒险活动以外，该公园还是联合国教科文组织指定的世界遗产和注册在案的国际黑暗天空公园，你可以在这里观赏到清澈的星空。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>玩耍的北极熊幼崽，卡克托维克，阿拉斯加州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/polarbearcubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:52:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/polarbearcubs/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Piriya Photography/Getty Images
今天是国际北极熊日，我们在欣赏这些“冰雪萌主”之际，也呼吁大家关注世界上最大的熊类所面临的挑战。国际北极熊日是由国际北极熊组织设立的，该组织致力于保护这些哺乳动物及其栖息地。选择这个日期是为了配合北极熊幼崽在洞穴中受到母亲保护的时间，因为这是北极熊一生中最脆弱的时期。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mist in the Cowichan Valley on Vancouver Island, British Columbia, Canada</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mtprevostduncan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:51:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/mtprevostduncan/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Kevin Oke/Alamy
Welcome to the Cowichan Valley on Vancouver Island in British Columbia. Located on the southern part of the island, this valley has art and history that echo through its green mountains, like Mount Prevost. The region is home to the band government of the Cowichan Tribes, the largest First Nations band in British Columbia. The city of Duncan has an impressive collection of indigenous art, including intricate carvings and paintings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>紅尾彗星蜂鳥</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/damilice_mansur_national_geographic_your_shot_2019031264093769/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 16:10:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/damilice_mansur_national_geographic_your_shot_2019031264093769/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Damilice Mansur, National Geographic Your Shot
攝影：Damilice Mansur， 國家地理〈你的觀點〉 一隻紅尾彗星蜂鳥 （red-tailed com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>公車上</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_ryan_harding_2022012670543945/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 15:50:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_ryan_harding_2022012670543945/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Photograph by Ryan Harding
這張照片攝於臺北，是我的系列攝影作品之一。我想記錄臺灣的生活風景，藉由聚焦於各種日常中普羅大眾各種異乎尋常、率直自然的有趣行為，呈現出一種復古、神祕而有如夢境般的感覺。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>傘花</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_vidhu_pillai_2022012664176357/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 15:30:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_vidhu_pillai_2022012664176357/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Photograph by Vidhu Pillai
季風時節，綿綿細雨之中出現一把繽紛的傘，像是地上開出一朵小花。攝於印度的克勒格布爾。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>追尋極光</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/peter_ribalchenko_2021050749944017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 15:20:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/peter_ribalchenko_2021050749944017/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Peter Ribalchenko
這張照片攝於挪威的阿爾塔市（Norway Alta City）。我從拉脫維亞一路開車過來，這是我第一次看到極光。我一輩子也忘不了這樣的美景。照片中是我本人。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>歲月流逝</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_anne_marcom_2022033161590053/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 14:30:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_anne_marcom_2022033161590053/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Photograph by Anne Marcom
黛拉是我救援回來的馬，雖然牠得了青光眼，一眼全盲、另一眼視力微弱，但牠的聽力非常好。牠聽到我在穀倉工作的聲音，就停下腳步細聽我的動靜，因為牠知道只要找到我，我就會給牠一根胡蘿蔔（而牠總是找得到我）。這是我從穀倉裡面往窗外拍到的黛拉和農場。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>黑暗王國中的一線光芒</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_denis_budkov__2022033161954869/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 14:10:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_denis_budkov__2022033161954869/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Photograph by Denis Budkov
攝於堪察加半島的穆特洛夫斯基火山。冬天時很多溪流上頭都積滿了雪，幾乎都沒有完全融化過，於是冰雪之下就形成了像這樣的冰洞隧道。這裡的雪在日積月累之下，厚度可達6公尺。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>口渴的蝴蝶</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/babak_moayedoddin_2021050749832877/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 13:40:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/babak_moayedoddin_2021050749832877/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Babak Moayedoddin
2011年2月攝於伊瓜蘇瀑布（Iguazu Falls）。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>河畔草原上的鬣狗</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yashodhan_bhatia_2021050750270745/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 08:20:05 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yashodhan_bhatia_2021050750270745/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Yashodhan Bhatia
我在2011年5月造訪維拉瓦達國家公園（Velavadar National Park），這趟旅程基本上非常慘烈，因為夏天實在是太熱了。不過在離開前一天的傍晚，我很幸運地拍到這張照片。在夕陽餘暉照耀之下，這隻鬣狗在金黃色的草原中享受吹拂而過的微風，幾乎和周圍融為一體。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>アーモンド畑, 米国 カリフォルニア州 (© Jeffrey Lewis/Tandem Stills &#43; Motion)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/almondbloom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 06:00:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/almondbloom/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Jeffrey Lewis/Tandem Stills + Motion
ここは米国カリフォルニア州、夏は暑くて乾燥し、冬は冷涼で雨が多いという、アーモンドの栽培に理想的な気候条件を備えています。世界のアーモンドの約 80%、米国のアーモンドのすべてがこの州で栽培されています…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>锦里街上悬挂的红色中国灯笼，成都，中国四川省</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/laternfestival2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 02:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/laternfestival2024/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Philippe LEJEANVRE/Getty images
正月是农历的元月，古人称“夜”为“宵”，正月十五是一年中第一个月圆之夜，所以称正月十五为“元宵节”。元宵节习俗自古以来就以热烈喜庆的观灯习俗为主。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haghartsin修道院，迪利扬国家公园，亚美尼亚</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/haghartsinmonastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 02:00:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/haghartsinmonastery/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Alexey Kharitonov/Shutterstock
Haghartsin 修道院隐藏在亚美尼亚北部的森林之中，被迪利扬国家公园郁郁葱葱的风景所环绕，是亚美尼亚中世纪建筑的瑰宝。修道院的建筑群由几座华丽的建筑组成，包括圣母教堂、圣格雷戈里教堂和圣斯特帕诺斯教堂。这些建筑的历史可以追溯到10世纪，上面装饰着精雕细琢的石碑、十字拱门以及其他装饰物，展现了那个时代的精湛工艺。修道院的名字“Haghartsin”的意思是“鹰之舞”，它为那些想要感受亚美尼亚悠久历史的人提供了一个宁静的去处。当你漫步在幽静的庭院中，探索周围的森林时，一种永恒的感觉油然而生。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>邂逅優雅猛獸</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_lucia_griggi_2022012663738157/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 16:30:30 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/photograph_by_lucia_griggi_2022012663738157/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Photograph by Lucia Griggi
攝於斯里蘭卡的雅拉國家公園深處。我們在叢林中紮營時，偶然看到這頭豹從長草叢中走出來，穿過空地。牠毛色光亮、神情謹慎，十分戒備地經過我們附近。當時夕陽西斜，光線很棒，實在是令人難以忘懷的畫面。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>復活節島的騎野馬比賽</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/agustin_rodriguez_garcia_2021111262777037/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 14:40:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/agustin_rodriguez_garcia_2021111262777037/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Agustin Rodriguez Garcia
這是復活節島在2012年塔帕蒂文化節時舉辦的騎野馬比賽，兩位參賽者正在競逐冠軍。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>布莱顿海滩的彩虹小屋，墨尔本，维多利亚州，澳大利亚</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/brightonboxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 02:00:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/brightonboxes/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Prasit photo/Getty Images
布莱顿彩虹小屋位于墨尔本的布莱顿海滩上，它们在阳光下五彩斑斓，是经久不衰的历史遗迹。随着新增小屋的加入，其总数已达到96座，这些小屋已成为墨尔本最主要的旅游景点之一。彩虹小屋的历史和它们的外观一样“丰富多彩”。1860年，它们首次出现在布莱顿的海岸线上，为更换泳衣的游客提供简单的遮挡。在第一次世界大战后的经济萧条时期，这些沙滩小屋遭到了磨损和破坏，于1934年接受集体修复。尽管进行了维护，它们还是在1952年面临过被拆除的危机，后来通过布莱顿彩虹小屋协会的努力得以保留，所以我们今天依旧能欣赏到这些充满活力的“海岸警卫队”！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>火瀑布，优胜美地国家公园，加利福尼亚州，美国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yosemitefirefall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 02:00:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/yosemitefirefall/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing. copyright: © Gregory B Cuvelier/Shutterstock
想亲眼目睹炙热的“火瀑布”吗？您没有听错，在优胜美地国家公园里就看到这样一个不可思议的景象。“火瀑布”是季节性瀑布，在冬季和早春时节，当降雪量充足且气温升高到足以融化积雪时，瀑布就会流下来。在二月份的几个星期里，如果天气晴朗，水流正常，而阳光照射的角度又恰到好处时，这条细长的瀑布就会呈现出火焰般的光彩。每年这个时候，会有上百名游客聚集在优胜美地山谷观赏这一奇特迷人的自然景象，山谷里人挤人，连找位置观赏都是一种挑战。有趣的是，这种自然现象被称为“火瀑布”，也是对历史上著名的“优胜美地国家公园火瀑布”的致敬，在1872年至1968年，公园里举办过“人造火瀑布”活动，主办方将余火未尽的木块、煤块推到悬崖下，在黑夜中形成一道炽热亮眼的“火瀑布”。随着时间的推移，公园管理员逐渐认识到这不是一个明智的主意，最终取消了这一活动。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>自然之心</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gail_farah_2022012663516469/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 17:20:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/gail_farah_2022012663516469/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Gail Farah
新萌發的蕨葉剛好形成一個心形，非常可愛。我拍下這張照片的時間剛剛好，到隔天它就不再是這個形狀了。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>往上看</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/francis_audet_2022033161233965/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 15:51:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/francis_audet_2022033161233965/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Francis Audet
有時候抬頭往上面看看，會見識到不同的景致，尤其是在季節交替、大自然色彩繽紛的時候！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大象與長頸鹿</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/susan_mcconnell_2022033160717893/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 14:10:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/susan_mcconnell_2022033160717893/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Susan McConnell
照片中是納米比亞埃托沙國家公園裡的大象和長頸鹿。我以貼近地面的角度拍攝，將這兩種具有代表性的大型動物用有趣的比例呈現出來。攝影資訊：快門1/250s，光圈f/8.0，ISO400，50mm。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>燃燒的仙女棒</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/liton_chowdhury_2022033161415249/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 12:30:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/liton_chowdhury_2022033161415249/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Liton Chowdhury
女兒玩仙女棒的景象，讓我覺得既美好又魔幻。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>玩耍的小北極狐</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/irit_abramovich_2022033161064541/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 12:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/irit_abramovich_2022033161064541/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Irit Abramovich
夏日暖陽下，兩隻小北極狐在阿爾克霍恩（位於斯瓦爾巴群島）的岩岸上玩得不亦樂乎；牠們的母親外出狩獵去了，不在身邊。看著牠們在野外自由自在的樣子，實在令人開心！</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>冬季抽象畫</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/daniel_jeffery_2022012669680745/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 11:50:13 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/daniel_jeffery_2022012669680745/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Daniel Jeffery
這張美麗的照片攝於明尼蘇達州，是我在這年第一場雪下完後，在一株黃背櫟（swamp oak）下抬頭看到的畫面。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>餵我餵我！</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jk_putnam_2022012669931929/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 11:30:19 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jk_putnam_2022012669931929/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: JK Putnam
攝於美國蒙大拿州的冰河國家公園。一隻河烏幼鳥正在向媽媽討食物，這種鳥類棲息在水流快速的山間溪流附近，會潛入水面下捕食水生昆蟲。為了養育幼鳥，母鳥孜孜不倦地在湍急的溪流中覓食，但是經常空手而回。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>鬼魂風箏</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/matteo_zin_2022033160900345/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 10:50:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/matteo_zin_2022033160900345/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia. copyright: Matteo Zin
霧氣籠罩著天空中鬼魂般的風箏，別有一股詭譎感。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>蛻皮</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/donald_jusa_2022033160575221/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:30:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/donald_jusa_2022033160575221/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Donald Jusa
我偶然發現正在蛻皮的昆蟲，便將這個自然現象的過程記錄下來。其中一隻已經完成蛻變，另一隻正進行到一半。這張照片是使用Nikon D90拍攝，搭配Tamron SP AF 90mm 微距鏡頭，放大倍率1:1，採手持攝影，光源為自然光。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>休息時光</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jaclyn_kessel_2022033161779885/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:10:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jaclyn_kessel_2022033161779885/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Jaclyn Kessel
我在義大利的「五漁村」捕捉到這一大一小在海邊放鬆的愉快時光。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>吃檸檬皮的羊群</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/steve_brockett_2022012670382825/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 09:00:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/steve_brockett_2022012670382825/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Steve Brockett
從空中拍攝在黑色荒漠土上吃檸檬皮的羊群，攝於西班牙南部的塔韋爾納斯。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>綠洲裡的老婦人</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/viola_macakova_2022012670653961/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 08:30:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/viola_macakova_2022012670653961/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Viola Macakova
我在曼谷著名的紅燈區牛仔街發現了這個地方。這條街十分熱鬧，滿街都是鋼管酒吧、妓女和脫衣舞孃。我經過一家吵吵嚷嚷的酒吧，看到一個個眼中毫無光彩的落寞女子，為了吸引男性顧客而擠出笑容、賣力舞動。相較之下，這間小店裡的老婦人彷彿處於沙漠中的綠洲。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>紅眼樹蛙</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/axel_hilger_2021050749351217/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 07:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/axel_hilger_2021050749351217/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Axel Hilger
哥斯大黎加的紅眼樹蛙（Agalychnis callidryas）在季風帶來的雨中，看起來好像有點錯愕。這張照片是我在雨中撐著傘，用Nikon相機拍攝的。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>藍色瓦拉那西</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/anton_jankovoy_2021050749696857/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 05:40:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/anton_jankovoy_2021050749696857/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Anton Jankovoy
街頭遇見的小男孩，攝於印度北方邦（Uttar Pradesh）的瓦拉那西（Varanasi）。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>深夜嬌客</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sammy_love_2022033162203073/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 05:30:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/sammy_love_2022033162203073/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Sammy Love
這張照片是7月時在我們位於賓夕法尼亞州科茨維爾的住家後院拍到的。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>轉綠</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lisa_runnels_2022012663843457/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 05:20:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lisa_runnels_2022012663843457/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Lisa Runnels
我在密西西比州一個叫做馬吉的小鎮上經過花店，發現了這些花。這張照片是在我買下花兒的兩週之後拍的，它們剛開始凋謝，拍起來別有一番美感。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>彩虹之下</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bob_cochran_2021050750076133/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 04:28:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/bob_cochran_2021050750076133/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Bob Cochran
我在大提頓國家公園（Grand Teton National Park）等待一場午後雷雨下完，看到這頭公駝鹿和兩隻母駝鹿在午睡。雨過天青，透出一抹虹彩，公駝鹿站起來望著天空，彷彿露出了微笑。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinder Scout，峰区国家公园，英国</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/peakdistrictnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 02:00:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/peakdistrictnp/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：bing copyright: © john finney photography/Getty Images
在英国峰区国家公园那片广阔的土地上，坐落着金德·斯科特自然保护区，它是英国历史上一次重要的人民运动的发生地。金德·斯科特海拔约2087英尺，是峰区的最高点，崎岖的荒野和狂风呼啸的高原吸引着世世代代的冒险家和自然爱好者前来探险。1932年，这里发生了历史性的大规模非法闯入事件，数百名民众徒步抗议要求公众可以自由进入这片领域，这一公民抗命运动促使了英国国家公园立法的通过。峰区国家公园的建立使得这里的丘陵和山谷得到保护，成为生态资源，供后人享受，同时也标志着对大众通行权以及自然资源的保护工作取得了重大胜利。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>有志者事竟成</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jason_kaplan_2021050749497733/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 01:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/jason_kaplan_2021050749497733/</guid>
      <description>图文来源自：netgeomedia copyright: Jason Kaplan
納森．米德（Nathan Meader）在尼克．布羅德（Nick Broeder）的繫繩協助之下，完成了這趟攀岩，他從中繼固定點垂降下來，然後兩人在此休息過夜。在我開始曝光攝影前，有另一個攀岩隊成功登頂然後回到地面，可以看出他們移動的路線。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toledo, Spain (© Carlos Fernandez/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tajoriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:46:16 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/tajoriver/</guid>
      <description>Toledo, a city situated in the Castilla-La Mancha region of Spain, is known for its unique geography. Positioned on a raised mass of land, the city is embraced by the Tagus River on three sides. This splendid city was called &amp;lsquo;The City of Three Cultures&amp;rsquo; during the Middle Ages, where Christian, Muslim and Jewish communities coexisted harmoniously. Toledo has been a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 1986, and its historical core is packed with mosques, synagogues and an impressive Gothic cathedral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lincoln Memorial, Washington, DC (© Steve Whiston/Fallen Log Photography/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lincolnsunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/lincolnsunset/</guid>
      <description>The United States of America has had 46 commanders in chief, and today, the third Monday of February, we commemorate their legacies. Initially established to honor George Washington&amp;rsquo;s birthday, Presidents Day has evolved into a celebration of all presidents. Revered among them is Abraham Lincoln, a towering figure in American history, who guided the country through the Civil War and abolished slavery in America. The Lincoln Memorial, seen in today&amp;rsquo;s image, overlooks the Reflecting Pool at the west end of the National Mall in Washington, DC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>乱れて咲くしだれ梅の花, 京都府 京都市 (© EvergreenPlanet/Getty Images)</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ume2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 18:45:15 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/ume2024/</guid>
      <description>梅の花が咲き誇る季節がやってきました。桜に先駆けて咲き始める寒さに負けないこの花は、春の訪れや忍耐などの象徴として古くから日本人に愛され、古典文学や俳句にもよく登場します…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>鸟瞰克鲁斯港色彩斑斓的房屋，特内里费岛，西班牙</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnavaltenerife/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 17:34:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/carnavaltenerife/</guid>
      <description>这些色彩斑斓的街道之间发生了什么？想象下有这样一个地方，大西洋轻抚着色彩斑斓的海岸，泰德峰从3715米的高度俯瞰着它。这个地方就是特内里费岛，西班牙加那利群岛上一个风景秀美四季如春的天堂。但当二月来临时，这座岛屿就会焕然一新：这是独属于圣克鲁斯-德特内里费的狂欢节时间，其视觉效果和节日盛况可与著名的巴西里约热内卢狂欢节相媲美，也被认为是世界上第二热门和知名的狂欢节。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Hoag&#39;s Object: A Nearly Perfect Ring Galaxy </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 02:00:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708279225679_esa/</guid>
      <description>Is this one galaxy or two? This question came to light in 1950 when astronomerchanced upon this unusual extragalactic object. On the outside is a dominated by bright blue stars,while near the center lies a ball of much redder starsthat are likely much older. Between the two is a that appears almost completely dark. How formed, including its nearly of stars and gas, remains unknown. Genesis hypotheses include abillions of years ago and the gravitational effect of a that has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Meteor over the Bay of Naples </title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 05:42:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708206152288_eyes_at_night/</guid>
      <description>A cosmic dust grain plowing throughthe upper atmosphere much faster thancreated this brilliant.In a serendipitous moment, the sublime night sky view wascaptured from the resort island of Capri, in the Bay of Naples,on the evening of February 8.Looking across the bay, the camera faces northeast towardthe lights of Naples and surrounding cities.Pointing toward the horizon, theby chance ends above the silhouette of Mount Vesuvius.One of planet Earth&amp;rsquo;s most famous volcanos, an eruption ofdestroyed the city of Pompeii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pragser Wildsee in the Dolomites, South Tyrol, Italy</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195777754_hpquiz_20240217_lakedolomites/</guid>
      <description>The Pragser Wildsee, set among the majestic Dolomites, is an Alpine jewel also known as Lake Braies. Its crystal waters reflect the impressive peaks of the Dolomites, surrounded by green forests. Accessible via a scenic trail, the lake attracts visitors for hikes and walks during the mild seasons. In summer, it turns into a destination for relaxing boat rides, while in winter the landscape takes on unique magic. The Pragser Wildsee is a mix of natural beauty, history, and culture, with the little church of St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>抹香鲸浮出水面，多米尼克</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 02:49:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/blog/1708195747248_hpquiz_20240218_dominicawhales/</guid>
      <description>嗨，海中的巨人们！世界鲸鱼日与加勒比海多米尼克岛沿岸的抹香鲸一起再次浮出水面。这个节日于1980年在毛伊岛设立，最初是为了庆祝夏威夷水域的座头鲸，现在已经演变成一个倡导保护所有鲸鱼物种的全球性活动。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
https://github.com/yuin/goldmark https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://alisonjoe.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alisonjoe.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>壁纸自助网站
Written in Go, Hugo is an open source static site generator available under the Apache Licence 2.0. Hugo supports TOML, YAML and JSON data file types, Markdown and HTML content files and uses shortcodes to add rich content. Other notable features are taxonomies, multilingual mode, image processing, custom output formats, HTML/CSS/JS minification and support for Sass SCSS workflows.
Hugo makes use of a variety of open source projects including:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
